        // Complete EMG/NCS Flashcard Database - All Cards\n        // Extracted from original Anki database\n        NCSApp.flashcardData = [\n            {\n                question: "Trapezius upperNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Trapezius upperNerve: **Spinal accessory**Roots: **C3, C4::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632583832411\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: [...]Root: [...]",\n                answer: "Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: **Dorsal scapular**Root: **C5::1**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632584659631\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Serratus anteriorNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Serratus anteriorNerve: **Long thoracic**Roots: **C5, C6, C7::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632585459577\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: [...] Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: **Lateral pectoral; Medial pectoral::2** Roots: **C5, C6, C7, C8, T1::**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632585980961\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Latissimus dorsiNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Latissimus dorsiNerve: **Thoracodorsal**Roots: **C6, C7, C8::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632586355131\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minorNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minorNerve: **Suprascapular, Suprascapular, Axillary::3**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632602639458\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Deltoid Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Deltoid Nerve: **Axillary**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632603210049\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Biceps & BrachialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Biceps & BrachialisNerve: **Musculocutaneous. \"70% have dual radial n. (brachialis)\"**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632603825345\n            },\n            {\n                question: "BrachioradialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "BrachioradialisNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632604220448\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Extensor carpi radialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Extensor carpi radialisNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C6, C7::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632604586453\n            },\n            {\n                question: "TricepsNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "TricepsNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C6, C7, C8::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632604987361\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Pronator teresNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Pronator teresNerve: **Median**Roots: **C6, C7::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632605382915\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Flexor carpi radialisNerve: [...]Nerve Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Flexor carpi radialisNerve: **Median**Nerve Roots: **C6, C7::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632605712159\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: **Radial (Posterior interosseous branch)**Roots: **C7, C8::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632606650556\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve:Digits 2 & 3 [...] Digits 4 & 5 [...] Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve:Digits 2 & 3 **Ant. interosseous branch of median** Digits 4 & 5 **Ulnar** Roots: **C7, C8, T1::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632607927259\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Flexor digitorum superficialis**Nerve: **Median**Roots: **C7, C8, T1::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632608454705\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Flexor pollicis longus**Nerve: **Ant. interosseous of median nerve.**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632609063882\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Abductor pollicis brevisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Abductor pollicis brevisNerve: **Median nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632609333324\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Opponens pollicis Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Opponens pollicis Nerve: **Median nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632609678977\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Adductor pollicis**Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632609993443\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**First dorsal & abd dig minimi, dorsal interosseus** Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632610198911\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Subscapularis nerve: [...]roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Subscapularis nerve: **Upper and lower subscapular nerves::2**roots: **C5, C6::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632668240414\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Flexor Carpi Ulnaris** Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632668793027\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] nerve: [...] roots: [...] \"no major\"",\n                answer: "**Extensor Pollicis Longus and Brevis** nerve: **Posterior interosseous branch of the radial nerve** roots: **C7, C8::2** \"no major\"",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1632669279060\n            },\n            {\n                question: "IliacusNerve: [...]Roots: [...] no majorpsoasNerve: [...]Roots: [...] no major",\n                answer: "IliacusNerve: **Femoral**Roots: **L2, L3** no majorpsoasNerve: **lumbar spinal nerves**Roots: ** L1, L2 and L3** no major",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634494760413\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Gluteus medius/min & tensor fascia::3**Nerve: **Superior gluteal**Roots: **L4, L5, S1::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634495044155\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Gluteus maximus**Nerve: **Inferior gluteal**Roots: **L5, S1, S2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634495281811\n            },\n            {\n                question: "QuadricepsNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "QuadricepsNerve: **Femoral**Roots: **L2, L3, L4::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634495520352\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Tibialis anterior::m.**Nerve: **Deep peroneal**Roots: **L4, L5::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634495698652\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Extensor hallucis longusNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Extensor hallucis longusNerve: **Deep peroneal**Roots: **L5, S1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634495916107\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Flexor hallucis longusNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Flexor hallucis longusNerve: **Tibial**Roots: **L5, S1, S2::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634496143730\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Tibialis posterior**Nerve: **Tibial**Roots: **L5, S1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634496357419\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "**Peroneus longus & brevis::2**Nerve: **Superficial peroneal**Roots: **L5, S1::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634496519285\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Gastrocnemius & soleus: Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",\n                answer: "Gastrocnemius & soleus: Nerve: **Tibial**Roots: **S1, S2::2**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634496682784\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...] no major",\n                answer: "**Adductor Magnus, Longus, Brevis::1 of 3** Nerve: **Obturator nerve**Roots: **L2, L3, L4::3** no major",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634497130711\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Biceps Femoris (long & Short, Semimembranosus, and Semitendinosus) Nerve: [...] Roots: [...] no major",\n                answer: "Biceps Femoris (long & Short, Semimembranosus, and Semitendinosus) Nerve: **sciatic nerve Tibial division & common peroneal division (to short head of biceps femoris)::2 + caveat** Roots: **L5, S1, S2::3** no major",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634497501648\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is an injury to sheath of the nerve (but the axon remains intact.)translates to slower signal conduction (onset/peak latency +/- duration) along the axon.",\n                answer: "**demyelination** is an injury to sheath of the nerve (but the axon remains intact.)translates to slower signal conduction (onset/peak latency +/- duration) along the axon.",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634824812838\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons)is known as [...] It can present as a [...] drop in [...] with stim. [...]",\n                answer: "Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons)is known as **conduction block.** It can present as a **>20% - >50%::%range2#'s** drop in **CMAP amplitude** with stim. **across the area of injury or L/R comparison::location 2**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634825217345\n            },\n            {\n                question: "demyelination affects the speed of signal conduction along a nervethus NCS's (CMAP and SNAP) parameters effected include:[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "demyelination affects the speed of signal conduction along a nervethus NCS's (CMAP and SNAP) parameters effected include:**o/p latency****CV****duration (temporal dispersion)**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634825966117\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] injuries affect the amplitude on nerve conduction waveform",\n                answer: "**Axonal** injuries affect the amplitude on nerve conduction waveform",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634826379576\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: A nerve injury that begins in a “dying back” fashion and affects the nerve distally and ascends proximally[...]: A nerve injury that degenerates distally. The nerve segment proximal to the injury site is essentially intact",\n                answer: "**Axonal Degeneration**: A nerve injury that begins in a “dying back” fashion and affects the nerve distally and ascends proximally**Wallerian Degeneration**: A nerve injury that degenerates distally. The nerve segment proximal to the injury site is essentially intact",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634826588748\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unitresults in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury):[...] [...] [...]",\n                answer: "**Collateral sprouting** is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unitresults in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury):**polyphasic waveforms** **increased duration** **increased amplitude**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634827686906\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original pathIt will travel approximately [...]/d or [...]mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact.",\n                answer: "**Axonal regrowth** is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original pathIt will travel approximately **1 mm**/d or **1 in./**mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact.",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634827804416\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sunderland ClassificationTYPE 1[...]TYPE 2[...]TYPE 3Type 2 + [...] injuryTYPE 4Type 3 + [...] injuryTYPE 5Type 4 + [...]",\n                answer: "Sunderland ClassificationTYPE 1**Conduction block (neuropraxia)::2**TYPE 2**Axonal injury (axonotmesis)::2**TYPE 3Type 2 + **Endoneurium** injuryTYPE 4Type 3 + **Perineurium** injuryTYPE 5Type 4 + **Epineurium injury (neurotmesis)::2**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634844708560\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is A theoretical local block that occurs when reversing the stimulator’s cathode and anode. This hyperpolarizes the nerve, thus inhibiting the production of an action potential",\n                answer: "**Anodal Block** is A theoretical local block that occurs when reversing the stimulator’s cathode and anode. This hyperpolarizes the nerve, thus inhibiting the production of an action potential",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634845635485\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS)stimulus intensity set too [...] - [...]- Amplitudes [...]stimulus intensity set too [...] - falsely [...] - falsely [...]",\n                answer: "**Supramaximal stimulus** stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS)stimulus intensity set too **high** - **Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes)**- Amplitudes **remain unchanged**stimulus intensity set too **low** - falsely **lower amplitude** - falsely **prolonged latency**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634846151435\n            },\n            {\n                question: "process of averaging improves the [...] by a factor that is the square root of the number of averages performed.",\n                answer: "process of averaging improves the **Signal to Noise Ratio (S:N)** by a factor that is the square root of the number of averages performed.",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634846534576\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Stimulus ArtifactThis is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized byAppropriate: [...] placement[...]",\n                answer: "Stimulus ArtifactThis is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized byAppropriate: **ground and stimulator (anode and cathode)::equipment factor 2** placement**Cleansing the skin from dirt, perspiration, and lotions::pt factor**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634846665871\n            },\n            {\n                question: "A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing [...] and the vertical axis representing [...] or gaineach cube is a [...]",\n                answer: "A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing **sweep speed (msec)::name, unit** and the vertical axis representing **sensitivity (mV)::name, unit** or gaineach cube is a **division**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634855351602\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is the time required for an electrical stimulus to initiate an evoked potential (fastest axon)[...] is the time for the majority of the axons",\n                answer: "**Onset/distal latency (CMAP)** is the time required for an electrical stimulus to initiate an evoked potential (fastest axon)**Peak latency (SNAP)** is the time for the majority of the axons",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634857611089\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the [...]Normal values are generally >[...] m/sec in the upper limbs and >[...] m/sec in the lower limbs",\n                answer: "**conduction velocity** is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the **myelin**Normal values are generally >**50** m/sec in the upper limbs and >**40** m/sec in the lower limbs",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634857821391\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG/NCS Conduction VelocityCV for a newborn is 50% that of an adult. At 1 year, it is 80% that of an adult. It is equal to an adult by [...] yearsAfter the [...] decade, the CV decreases [...] m/sec per decade",\n                answer: "EMG/NCS Conduction VelocityCV for a newborn is 50% that of an adult. At 1 year, it is 80% that of an adult. It is equal to an adult by **3–5::#~#** yearsAfter the **5th** decade, the CV decreases **1–2::range** m/sec per decade",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634858756029\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibersCMAP (or SNAP) [...] reductions are due to injury to [...]",\n                answer: "**Amplitude** reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibersCMAP (or SNAP) **amplitude::same** reductions are due to injury to **axons**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634859337870\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing.it is a measure of [...] of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing",\n                answer: "**duration::NCS parameter** is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing.it is a measure of **synchrony** of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634859587160\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] reflects the range of conduction velocities of the fastest and slowest nerve fibers.",\n                answer: "**Temporal dispersion** reflects the range of conduction velocities of the fastest and slowest nerve fibers.",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634860078926\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring oneswhen comparing a [...] stimulation, a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.)amplitude drop of [...] is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAPamplitude drop of [...] is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP",\n                answer: "**Phase Cancellation** = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring oneswhen comparing a **proximal to distal** stimulation, a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.)amplitude drop of **50%::%** is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAPamplitude drop of **15%::%** is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1634899647729\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SNAPs are normal in [...] injury",\n                answer: "SNAPs are normal in **Pre-ganglionic::pre/post** injury",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635019472566\n            },\n            {\n                question: "active and reference pickup should be [...] cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by [...] them allSave for [...] which will still be normal",\n                answer: "active and reference pickup should be **> 4:: >/</#** cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by **decreasing::inceasing/decreasing** them allSave for **onset latency** which will still be normal",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635019716271\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CMAP potential should be [...] with an initial [...] deflection",\n                answer: "CMAP potential should be **biphasic::morphology** with an initial **negative (upward)** deflection",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635020127681\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to...1.) [...]2.) [...]3.) [...]",\n                answer: "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to...1.) **Inappropriate placement of active electrode (from MP)**2.) **conduction from other muscles (stim^)**3.) **Anomalous innervations (M. gruber)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635020914592\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to...[...][...] [...]",\n                answer: "Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to...**active and reference electrodes too close together****position off from motor point** **submaximal stimulation**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635021140498\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is an NCS analogue to a monosynaptic reflex",\n                answer: "**H-reflex** is an NCS analogue to a monosynaptic reflex",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635041533555\n            },\n            {\n                question: "H-reflex is initiated with a [...] at a [...] duration (1.0 msec).causing an [...] [...] response to the spinal cord, and then an [...] [...] response back to the electrode",\n                answer: "H-reflex is initiated with a **submaximal stimulus** at a **long** duration (1.0 msec).causing an **orthodromic::ortho/anti** **sensory::motor/sensory** response to the spinal cord, and then an **orthodromic::ortho/anti** **motor::motor/sensory** response back to the electrode",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635041785457\n            },\n            {\n                question: "H-reflex limitations1) [...] 2) [...]3) [...]",\n                answer: "H-reflex limitations1) **can not localize lesion** 2) **cannot distinguish between acute and chronic**3) **NOT a specific finding to S1 radiculopathy**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635042321707\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP. It is produced using a [...] duration, [...] stimulation",\n                answer: "**F-wave** is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP. It is produced using a **short** duration, **supramaximal** stimulation",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635042859845\n            },\n            {\n                question: "F-wave May be helpful in polyneuropathies and [...] but not overly useful in radiculopathies",\n                answer: "F-wave May be helpful in polyneuropathies and **plexopathies** but not overly useful in radiculopathies",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635043035494\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In [...] morphology and latency remain constant with each stimulation at the appropriate intensity",\n                answer: "In **H-reflex::F/H** morphology and latency remain constant with each stimulation at the appropriate intensity",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635043806903\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG increased insertional activity may be seen in both [...] and [...] conditions",\n                answer: "EMG increased insertional activity may be seen in both **neuropathic** and **myopathic** conditions",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635280551223\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG rare conditions, where [...] has occurred, insertional activity may be decreased",\n                answer: "EMG rare conditions, where **muscle atrophy** has occurred, insertional activity may be decreased",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635280677487\n            },\n            {\n                question: "a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur:1.) [...] which sound like a [...] 2.) [...] which sound like a [...]",\n                answer: "a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur:1.) **MEPPs (EP noise)** which sound like a **sea-shell murmur** 2.) **EPPs (EP spikes)** which sound like a **sputtering fat**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635343921792\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG: spontaneous activity at rest (not NMJ) in general represents [...] of muscle",\n                answer: "EMG: spontaneous activity at rest (not NMJ) in general represents **denervation** of muscle",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635344950262\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Both fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves are usually seen together in [...] muscle EMG, hallmarks are sounding like (Fib): [...] and (Psw): [...] and their [...] of firing",\n                answer: "Both fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves are usually seen together in **denervated** muscle EMG, hallmarks are sounding like (Fib): **\"rain on a tin roof”** and (Psw): **\"dull thuds\"** and their **regularity::timing** of firing",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635345446958\n            },\n            {\n                question: "a numeric grading scale to quantify fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves on a scale from _ to _ [...]",\n                answer: "a numeric grading scale to quantify fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves on a scale from _ to _ **+1 to +4**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635345626379\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]",\n                answer: "**Fibrillation potentials::wave form**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635348955146\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]",\n                answer: "**Complex repetitive discharges::wave form**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635348979166\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] sound like a [...] spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by [...] 2/2 [...]",\n                answer: "**complex repetetive discharges** sound like a **motor boat** spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by **ephaptic transmission** 2/2 **collateral sprouting**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635349652423\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]",\n                answer: "**Myotonic discharges**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635349679112\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] are classicly associated w/ [...] [...] single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a [...] sound",\n                answer: "**myotonic discharges** are classicly associated w/ **myopathies::disease category** **biphasic::waveform** single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a **“dive bomber”** sound",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635349963884\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] has the appearance of a MUAP with an [...] firing patternIts hallmark sign is a much [...] frequency with a [...] sound",\n                answer: "**fasciculation** has the appearance of a MUAP with an **irregular** firing patternIts hallmark sign is a much **slower** frequency with a **“corn popping”** sound",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635350242203\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: rhythmic groups of MUAPs firing repetitivelyclinicaly present as slow continuous [...] sounds like [...] hallmark sign is the [...] within and between each discharge",\n                answer: "**Myokymic discharges**: rhythmic groups of MUAPs firing repetitivelyclinicaly present as slow continuous **“worm-like” quivering** sounds like **“marching soldiers.”** hallmark sign is the **semi-regularity** within and between each discharge",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635354513231\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Myokymic discharges are most commonly seen in [...]",\n                answer: "Myokymic discharges are most commonly seen in **radiated-induced neuropathy**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635354589536\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic [...] sound and [...] appearance",\n                answer: "**Neuromyotonic discharges**: high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic **“pinging”** sound and **Tornado-like** appearance",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635355111069\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Neuromyotonic discharges classically seen in [...].",\n                answer: "Neuromyotonic discharges classically seen in **neuromyotonia (Isaac’s syndrome)::eponym**.",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635355218931\n            },\n            {\n                question: "exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a [...]unlike CMAP initial deflection is [...]. can consist of up to [...] phases",\n                answer: "exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a **MUAP**unlike CMAP initial deflection is **- or +**. can consist of up to **4** phases",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635356223797\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MUAP amplitude: represents the muscle fiber density, measured from the most positive to the most negative peakIt can be increased from [...], A sign that inury is becoming [...]",\n                answer: "MUAP amplitude: represents the muscle fiber density, measured from the most positive to the most negative peakIt can be increased from **reinnervation**, A sign that inury is becoming **chronic::timing**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635356761982\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MUAP Rise Time: represents the time it takes the MUAP to go from trough to the peak of the negative wave. It represents [...] to the motor unit.",\n                answer: "MUAP Rise Time: represents the time it takes the MUAP to go from trough to the peak of the negative wave. It represents **needle position** to the motor unit.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635356972387\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MUAP Duration increases (>15 msec) as the motor unit territory increases 2/2 [...]",\n                answer: "MUAP Duration increases (>15 msec) as the motor unit territory increases 2/2 **collateral sprouting/reinervation::pathology**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635357066029\n            },\n            {\n                question: "polyphasicity (5 phases) results from [...] and is [...] in timing however, this can occur normally 15% [...] or 30% [...] or in the elderly",\n                answer: "polyphasicity (5 phases) results from **reinnervation/collateral sprouting::patho-phys** and is **chronic** in timing however, this can occur normally 15% **(concentric needle)** or 30% **(monopolar needle)** or in the elderly",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635357257414\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP. 2/2 early [...] → very slowly conducting",\n                answer: "**satellite potentitals**: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP. 2/2 early **re-inervation** → very slowly conducting",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635441527779\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ [...] (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise",\n                answer: "**cramp discharge** spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ **metabolic disturbances** (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635441729623\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween [...] and [...] diseases",\n                answer: "**Recruitment** refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween **neruopathic** and **myopathic** diseases",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635442490969\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG MUAP recruitment pattern follows: \"The rule of [...]\"",\n                answer: "EMG MUAP recruitment pattern follows: \"The rule of **5's**\"",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635442589329\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] most commonly seen in myopathic conditions that result in a loss of muscle fibers.",\n                answer: "**Early recruitment::recruitment pattern** most commonly seen in myopathic conditions that result in a loss of muscle fibers.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635442835550\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] most commonly seen in neuropathic conditions",\n                answer: "**Reduced recruitment::recruitment pattern** most commonly seen in neuropathic conditions",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635442892105\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor unit recruitment. (A) Normal. (B) [...] (C) [...]",\n                answer: "Motor unit recruitment. (A) Normal. (B) **Early (myopathic)** (C) **Decreased (neuropathic)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1635442996549\n            },\n            {\n                question: "this is a [...] needle electrode",\n                answer: "this is a **Monopolar** needle electrode",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1642360144912\n            },\n            {\n                question: "this is a [...] needle electrode",\n                answer: "this is a **Concentric** needle electrode",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1642360215210\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Monopolar needle advantages (PM&R)Records more [...] and larger [...]",\n                answer: "Monopolar needle advantages (PM&R)Records more **positive sharp waves (more abnormal activity in general)** and larger **MUAP's**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1642360548139\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Concentric needle advantagesless [...]",\n                answer: "Concentric needle advantagesless **interference**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1642360628814\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: results from [...] muscle fibersthat are [...] by [...]",\n                answer: "**complex repetetive discharge::EMG wave form**: results from **denervated** muscle fibersthat are **reinnervated** by **collateral sprouting**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1644938245116\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: spontaneous discharges originating from the [...] or its [...] prior to its terminal branchesresults in [...] muscle fiber contractionIf associated with [...], they are considered pathological",\n                answer: "**fasciculation**: spontaneous discharges originating from the **motor neuron** or its **axon** prior to its terminal branchesresults in **intermittent::timing** muscle fiber contractionIf associated with **FIBs or PSWs**, they are considered pathological",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1644938661000\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] EMG finding are associated with [...] diseases (broad category)",\n                answer: "**fasciculations** EMG finding are associated with **Anterior horn cell** diseases (broad category)",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1644938837151\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy (sensory vs motor)most commonly presents as: [...] complaints, [...] complaints, or [...] complaints\"in descending order\"",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy (sensory vs motor)most commonly presents as: **pure sensory** complaints, **sensori-motor** complaints, or **pure motor** complaints\"in descending order\"",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456299854\n            },\n            {\n                question: "RadiculopathyNCSs are typically [...]",\n                answer: "RadiculopathyNCSs are typically **normal**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456352724\n            },\n            {\n                question: "RadiculopathyA pure sensory injury would demonstrate a [...] EMG.",\n                answer: "RadiculopathyA pure sensory injury would demonstrate a **negative** EMG.",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456399829\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy[...] occur without structural abnormalities on MRI or EMG",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy**can::can / cannot** occur without structural abnormalities on MRI or EMG",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456482021\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Unncommon Radiculopathy causesH—[...]I—[...]M—[...]A—[...]D—[...]A—[...]M—[...]",\n                answer: "Unncommon Radiculopathy causesH—**Herpes zoster**I—**Inflammatory::whole category**M—**Metastasis**A—**Arachnoiditis**D—**Diabetes mellitus**A—**Abscess**M—**Mass**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456691843\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy common cuases include [...] and [...]",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy common cuases include **herniated disc** and **spinal stenosis**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456744529\n            },\n            {\n                question: "role of NCS in Radiculopathy is to evaluate [...] to explain the patient’s symptoms",\n                answer: "role of NCS in Radiculopathy is to evaluate **superimposed pathology** to explain the patient’s symptoms",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645456959463\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located [...] to the DRGCMAP: Normal or reduced amplitudeCMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is...purely [...][...] or[...] has already occurred(not snesory)",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located **proximal** to the DRGCMAP: Normal or reduced amplitudeCMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is...purely **demyelinating****incomplete** or**reinnervation** has already occurred(not snesory)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645457114777\n            },\n            {\n                question: "H-reflex: Possibly abnormal in an [...] radiculopathy but not pathognomonic",\n                answer: "H-reflex: Possibly abnormal in an **S1** radiculopathy but not pathognomonic",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645457156251\n            },\n            {\n                question: "F-waves: [...] sensitive / specific for a radiculopathy.",\n                answer: "F-waves: **Not::are / are not** sensitive / specific for a radiculopathy.",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645457219206\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG for Dx radiculopathyabnormal findings in [...] muscles innervated by the same [...] but different [...]",\n                answer: "EMG for Dx radiculopathyabnormal findings in **two or more::#** muscles innervated by the same **spinal nerve root** but different **peripheral nerves**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645458276223\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG for Dx radiculopathyIdeally, [...] muscles ([...] peripheral muscles + [...]) should be evaluated",\n                answer: "EMG for Dx radiculopathyIdeally, **6** muscles (**5** peripheral muscles + **paraspinals**) should be evaluated",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645458442560\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG Radiculopathy DxClassically, [...] found in [...] different muscles innervated by different peripheral nerves but same spinal root.",\n                answer: "EMG Radiculopathy DxClassically, **FIBs or PSWs::2** found in **2::#** different muscles innervated by different peripheral nerves but same spinal root.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645458674630\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG Radiculopathy DxFibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: [...][...][...]incomplete or missed by random sampling",\n                answer: "EMG Radiculopathy DxFibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: **demyelinating****pure sensory****chronic**incomplete or missed by random sampling",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645458765425\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates [...] responses of the nervous system to an [...]. SSEP's represent the function of the [...] pathway using afferent potentials",\n                answer: "Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates **time-locked** responses of the nervous system to an **external stimulus**. SSEP's represent the function of the **DCML** pathway using afferent potentials",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645460781827\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SSEP's initiated by a repetitive [...] stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the [...] or [...]",\n                answer: "SSEP's initiated by a repetitive **submaximal::intensity** stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the **spine** or **scalp**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645460999266\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Somatosensory evoked potential (SSEP) monitors for problems such as (a) [...], (b) [...], or (c) [...]",\n                answer: "Somatosensory evoked potential (SSEP) monitors for problems such as (a) **peripheral nerve injuries**, (b) **CNS lesions (eg. MS)**, or (c) **intraoperative monitoring (eg. spinal surgery)**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645461081074\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MS SSEP's are seen 90% of the time, with the lower limb more likely to be abnormal than the upper limb. most common abnormality is the prolonged [...]. Amplitude reduction or absence can also be seen",\n                answer: "MS SSEP's are seen 90% of the time, with the lower limb more likely to be abnormal than the upper limb. most common abnormality is the prolonged **interpeak latencies**. Amplitude reduction or absence can also be seen",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645461182084\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SSEP nerves most commonly used for testing are the [...] for the upper limb and the [...] nerve for the lower limb",\n                answer: "SSEP nerves most commonly used for testing are the **median** for the upper limb and the **tibial** nerve for the lower limb",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645461247846\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SSEP's[...] considered useful for radiculopathies",\n                answer: "SSEP's**are not::are / are not** considered useful for radiculopathies",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645461606685\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: Decreased [...]Decreased [...]Prolonged [...]Abnormal [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **0** daysAbnormality: Decreased **recruitment**Decreased **recruitment interval**Prolonged **F-wave**Abnormal **H-reflex**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645479841403\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: Decreased [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **4** daysAbnormality: Decreased **CMAP amplitude**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645479959457\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **7** daysAbnormality: **Abnormal spontaneous activity in the paraspinals::EMG finding and location**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645501859049\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **14** daysAbnormality: **Abnormal spontaneous activity in the limbs::EMG finding and location**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645501994296\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] days Abnormality: [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **21** days Abnormality: **Abnormal activity present in both the paraspinals and limbs::EMG finding and llocation**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645502140506\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] Abnormality: [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **5–6 weeks::2 #'s** Abnormality: **Reinnervation begins / polyphasic::EMG finding**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645502246398\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] Abnormality: [...]",\n                answer: "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **6 months to 1 year::2 #'s** Abnormality: **Increased amplitude from reinnervated motor unit**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645502319352\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury[...] causing a transient ischemia or edema with [...] Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to [...]",\n                answer: "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury**Focal compression** causing a transient ischemia or edema with **paranodal intussusceptions** Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to **peripheral neuropathies**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645548616098\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NCS of demeylinating injuries Latency is typicaly [...] and Amplitude is typically [...]",\n                answer: "NCS of demeylinating injuries Latency is typicaly **prolonged** and Amplitude is typically **normal**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645549591433\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CMAP with low amplitude can be 2/2... 1.) temporal dispersion or 2.) decreased # of axons [...] of the AP is prolonged in temporal dispersioncausing, [...] to remain the same",\n                answer: "CMAP with low amplitude can be 2/2... 1.) temporal dispersion or 2.) decreased # of axons **duration** of the AP is prolonged in temporal dispersioncausing, **area under the curve** to remain the same",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645549933849\n            },\n            {\n                question: "supramaximal stimulation is achieved by [...] until the [...] of the waveform is no longer increasing",\n                answer: "supramaximal stimulation is achieved by **increasing stimulation** until the **amplitude** of the waveform is no longer increasing",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645551959707\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar nerve studies measurement is a common source of errorit is best to keep the elbow [...] and in the [...] for the entire study",\n                answer: "Ulnar nerve studies measurement is a common source of errorit is best to keep the elbow **flexed 90o** and in the **same position** for the entire study",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645552005946\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Active electrode: The active electrode, also referred to as E1 or G1 should be placed over the...[...] during motor studies. directly over the [...] during sensory studies.",\n                answer: "Active electrode: The active electrode, also referred to as E1 or G1 should be placed over the...**muscle belly** during motor studies. directly over the **nerve** during sensory studies.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645552722252\n            },\n            {\n                question: "The reference electrode (sometimes called the E2 or G2) should be placed.. on a nearby [...]",\n                answer: "The reference electrode (sometimes called the E2 or G2) should be placed.. on a nearby **tendon or bone::2**",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645552788686\n            },\n            {\n                question: "When stimulating proximal and distal sites, the waveforms should be [...] in morphology and duration",\n                answer: "When stimulating proximal and distal sites, the waveforms should be **similar** in morphology and duration",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645552978621\n            },\n            {\n                question: "If you are not sure which nerve is being stimulated NCS, check for [...]",\n                answer: "If you are not sure which nerve is being stimulated NCS, check for **physiological response**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645553014774\n            },\n            {\n                question: "You can estimate the amount of axonal loss in an acute peripheral nerve lesionif you compare the amplitude of the CMAP to the [...]",\n                answer: "You can estimate the amount of axonal loss in an acute peripheral nerve lesionif you compare the amplitude of the CMAP to the **unaffected side**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645553174804\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] are muscle fiber AP's recorded from a injured muscle or muscle with impaired innervation",\n                answer: "**Positive sharp waves (PSWs)** are muscle fiber AP's recorded from a injured muscle or muscle with impaired innervation",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645553800315\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] are spontaneous AP's of single muscle fibers firing autonomously. This can occur in the presence of impaired innervation",\n                answer: "**Fibrillation potentials (fibs)** are spontaneous AP's of single muscle fibers firing autonomously. This can occur in the presence of impaired innervation",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645553944511\n            },\n            {\n                question: "‘denervation potentials’ is a misnomer for [...]. (ex fibs, PSW, CRD's, cramps, mokymic, and fascic)Irritation can be cuased by [...] and [...] muscle disease, and local muscle [...].",\n                answer: "‘denervation potentials’ is a misnomer for **spontaneous activity**. (ex fibs, PSW, CRD's, cramps, mokymic, and fascic)Irritation can be cuased by **metabolic** and **inflammatory** muscle disease, and local muscle **trauma**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645554388519\n            },\n            {\n                question: "analyzing motor unit morphologycan be made more accurate by freezing the screen or by using a [...]",\n                answer: "analyzing motor unit morphologycan be made more accurate by freezing the screen or by using a **trigger and delay line**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645555815392\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG MUAP Decreased amplitude may be seen in [...]",\n                answer: "EMG MUAP Decreased amplitude may be seen in **myopathies::dz category**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645556029913\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor unit [...] is a better measure of pathology than polyphasicity it will be [...] in neuropathic processesand [...] in myopathic disorders",\n                answer: "Motor unit **duration** is a better measure of pathology than polyphasicity it will be **increased** in neuropathic processesand **decreased** in myopathic disorders",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645557256185\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG no abnormal spontaneous activity should be noted in any of the [...] lesions unless there is conduction block, in which case you would find [...]",\n                answer: "EMG no abnormal spontaneous activity should be noted in any of the **demyelinating** lesions unless there is conduction block, in which case you would find **decreased recruitment**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645558118535\n            },\n            {\n                question: "(SNAPs) and (CMAPs) amplitudes begin to decrease within [...] after nerve injury.",\n                answer: "(SNAPs) and (CMAPs) amplitudes begin to decrease within **several days** after nerve injury.",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645558248386\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathysensory NCS are always [...] unless there is [...]",\n                answer: "Radiculopathysensory NCS are always **normal** unless there is **coexisting pathology e.g., carpal tunnel syndrome**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645559375259\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy if SNAP abnormalities are found, it is important to [...]",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy if SNAP abnormalities are found, it is important to **rule out other lesions**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645559407196\n            },\n            {\n                question: "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be [...]",\n                answer: "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be **normal**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645559679922\n            },\n            {\n                question: "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be normal*However, in a [...] lesion it may be affected",\n                answer: "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be normal*However, in a **severe radicular** lesion it may be affected",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645559756513\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathyeven if a lesion causes axonal damage, the CMAP amplitude could still be normal*because muscles have [...].",\n                answer: "Radiculopathyeven if a lesion causes axonal damage, the CMAP amplitude could still be normal*because muscles have **input from multiple nerve roots**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645559874992\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy In reinnervation with sprouting of collateral axons, MUAP abnormalities such as [...] and [...] motor units may be present",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy In reinnervation with sprouting of collateral axons, MUAP abnormalities such as **long duration** and **polyphasic** motor units may be present",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645560209990\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy Recruitment abnormalities, if seen... would be typical of a [...] recruitment patternincluding: [...] motor units firing at a [...] rate",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy Recruitment abnormalities, if seen... would be typical of a **neuropathic** recruitment patternincluding: **few** motor units firing at a **high** rate",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645560312184\n            },\n            {\n                question: "RadiculopathyEMG in general will be able to assess only [...] injury to motor fibers",\n                answer: "RadiculopathyEMG in general will be able to assess only **axonal** injury to motor fibers",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645560521274\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] are classified as affecting primarily [...], or both. and by part of the nerve predominantly affected – [...], or both",\n                answer: "**Peripheral neuropathies** are classified as affecting primarily **motor or sensory fibers**, or both. and by part of the nerve predominantly affected – **axon or myelin**, or both",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645560988200\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Most peripheral neuropathies affect the [...] segment of the nerve",\n                answer: "Most peripheral neuropathies affect the **distal** segment of the nerve",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645561053241\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG findings are usually [...] in peripheral neuropathy",\n                answer: "EMG findings are usually **negative** in peripheral neuropathy",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645561288328\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG findings are usually negative in peripheral neuropathy, unless there is an [...]",\n                answer: "EMG findings are usually negative in peripheral neuropathy, unless there is an **axonal motor neuropathy**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645561337699\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] – the entire length of the nerve displays a slower conduction velocity. This is typically seen in dz's such as [...] and [...]",\n                answer: "**Uniform demyelination** – the entire length of the nerve displays a slower conduction velocity. This is typically seen in dz's such as **Charcot–Marie–Tooth** and **leukodystrophy**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645561900391\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] – uneven degree of demyelination of different nerve fibers throughout the course of the nerve which presents as [...] Dz example:[...][...][...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "**Segmental demyelination** – uneven degree of demyelination of different nerve fibers throughout the course of the nerve which presents as **temporal dispersion** Dz example:**AIDP / CIDP****Arsenic****MM****AIDS****LYME****Leprosy**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562119245\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] – localized area of demyelinationwhich presents as a decrease in conduction velocity [...] the lesion ex. [...] usually evident if there is a more than [...] m/s drop",\n                answer: "**Focal nerve slowing** – localized area of demyelinationwhich presents as a decrease in conduction velocity **across** the lesion ex. **cubital tunnel or entrapment neuropathy** usually evident if there is a more than **10** m/s drop",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562369751\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] – an area of severe focal demyelination where AP cannot propagate. [...] amplitude with [...] stimulation",\n                answer: "**Conduction block** – an area of severe focal demyelination where AP cannot propagate. **decreased::nl or dec** amplitude with **proximal::proximal/distal** stimulation",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562554470\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CMAP amplitude distal to a conduction block will be [...]",\n                answer: "CMAP amplitude distal to a conduction block will be **unaffected::affected / unaffected**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562691517\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [...] to the lesion latencies/CV will be [...][...] EMG findings",\n                answer: "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation **both Distal & Proximal::distal or proximal** to the lesion latencies/CV will be **normal*::abnormal/normal****+::+/-** EMG findings",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562944991\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [...] to the lesion drop in amp [...]%",\n                answer: "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation **proximal::distal or proximal** to the lesion drop in amp **20-50::2 # range**%",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645562991097\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Pure axonal injuryEtiology: (a) focal crush(b) [...](c) [...](d) [...]NCS latency and CV will be [...] EMG activity will be [...]",\n                answer: "Pure axonal injuryEtiology: (a) focal crush(b) **stretch (traction)**(c) **transection**(d) **peripheral neuropathies**NCS latency and CV will be **normal::abdnormal/normal** EMG activity will be **abdnormal::abdnormal/normal**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645563422086\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes:[...][...][...] [...]",\n                answer: "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes:**FIBs****PSWs****Complex repetitive discharges** **Myotonic discharges**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645563805690\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes:[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes:**Fasciculation potentials*****Myokymic discharges****Neuromyotonic discharges****Cramp discharge**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645563879198\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] EMG activity",\n                answer: "**cramp discharges** EMG activity",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645564091618\n            },\n            {\n                question: "AIN branches from the median nerve innervate (3 P's):[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "AIN branches from the median nerve innervate (3 P's):**Flexor digitorum profundus (FDP 1 and 2)****Flexor pollicis longus (FPL)****Pronator quadratus (PQ)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645638675207\n            },\n            {\n                question: "through the carpal tunnel, the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous [...][...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "through the carpal tunnel, the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous **Lumbricals (1, 2)****Opponens pollicis****Abductor pollicis brevis****Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)****Digital cutaneous branches**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645639168857\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Median n. Course:runs medial to the [...] in the distal upper armcontinues down the humerus and runs under the [...] at the medial epicondyle the [...] overlies the nerve in the proximal forearmnerve then passes between the [...] muscle and continues down under the [...]",\n                answer: "Median n. Course:runs medial to the **brachial a.** in the distal upper armcontinues down the humerus and runs under the **ligament of Struthers** at the medial epicondyle the **antebrachial fascia** overlies the nerve in the proximal forearmnerve then passes between the **two heads of the PT** muscle and continues down under the **FDS muscle**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645639731345\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: 2 cm bone spur 3 to 6 cm proximal to the medial epicondyle. It is connected to the epicondyle by a ligament in 1% of the population",\n                answer: "**LIGAMENT OF STRUTHER**: 2 cm bone spur 3 to 6 cm proximal to the medial epicondyle. It is connected to the epicondyle by a ligament in 1% of the population",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645639951551\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ligament of Struthers EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal median [...] [...] at [...] siteEMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: [...]",\n                answer: "Ligament of Struthers EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal median **SNAP and CMAP::2 NCS tests** **conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp)::2 NCS paramaters** at **above elbow** siteEMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: **All (including the PT)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645640132038\n            },\n            {\n                question: "bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an [...]EDX pres: similar to the [...]",\n                answer: "bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an **ABG / venipuncture::2**EDX pres: similar to the **LOS**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645640298859\n            },\n            {\n                question: "General Rule of ThumbAn entrapment mononeuropathy: is commonly named for the muscle compressing the nerve. That muscle is usually [...]",\n                answer: "General Rule of ThumbAn entrapment mononeuropathy: is commonly named for the muscle compressing the nerve. That muscle is usually **unaffected::affected or unaffected**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645640526148\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal [...] SNAPsAbnormal CMAPs at [...] EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: [...]",\n                answer: "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal **median nerve*** SNAPsAbnormal CMAPs at **above elbow site::in conduction block** EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: **All EXCEPT the PT***",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645640628809\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex findingpt may demonstrate a positive [...] signor Inability to [...] Sensation is [...]",\n                answer: "Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex findingpt may demonstrate a positive **“OK”** signor Inability to **make a fist** Sensation is **spared**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645641052132\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]% of people with clinical carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) can have a normal EDX study",\n                answer: "**10**% of people with clinical carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) can have a normal EDX study",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645642342009\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] from concomitant DMT2 or cervical radiculopathy increases the risk of CTS",\n                answer: "**Double crush syndrome** from concomitant DMT2 or cervical radiculopathy increases the risk of CTS",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645642749114\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS clinical presSensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the [...]. Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: [...]",\n                answer: "CTS clinical presSensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the **base of the thumb**. Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: **“LOAF”**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645643462420\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS EDX findings [...] studies are more sensitive because larger fibers are more affected than the slightly smaller fibers",\n                answer: "CTS EDX findings **Sensory::Motor/Sensory** studies are more sensitive because larger fibers are more affected than the slightly smaller fibers",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645643662574\n            },\n            {\n                question: "median NCSsdemyelinating lesion at the carpal tunnel results in [...] of both motor and sensory if demyelination caused conduction block or axonal loss, the distal CMAP and SNAP [...] will be decreased",\n                answer: "median NCSsdemyelinating lesion at the carpal tunnel results in **prolonged distal latencies** of both motor and sensory if demyelination caused conduction block or axonal loss, the distal CMAP and SNAP **amplitudes** will be decreased",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645643994061\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS EDX studyThe study of [...] of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from [...]",\n                answer: "CTS EDX studyThe study of **distal segments** of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from **peripheral neuropathy**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644051626\n            },\n            {\n                question: "If CTS patient has normal \"routine\" median nerve conduction studies (NCS); further testing is performed using more sensitive NCSs known as [...]",\n                answer: "If CTS patient has normal \"routine\" median nerve conduction studies (NCS); further testing is performed using more sensitive NCSs known as **comparison studies (ie. median to ulnar)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644316751\n            },\n            {\n                question: "median-versus-ulnar comparison tests a difference of > [...] msec is considered abnormal",\n                answer: "median-versus-ulnar comparison tests a difference of > **0.5** msec is considered abnormal",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644384075\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: Prolonged latency plus decreased amplitudeCMAP: Prolonged latency",\n                answer: "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Moderate**SNAP: Prolonged latency plus decreased amplitudeCMAP: Prolonged latency",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644509642\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: Prolonged latency CMAP: Normal",\n                answer: "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Mild**SNAP: Prolonged latency CMAP: Normal",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644558959\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: AbsentCMAP: Prolonged latency and decr. Amplitude",\n                answer: "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Severe**SNAP: AbsentCMAP: Prolonged latency and decr. Amplitude",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645644599262\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: numbness or dysesthesias in 1st - 4th digits. sx exacerbated during sleep (most common sx) and relieved with wrist shaking",\n                answer: "**Mild CTS::CTS severity**: numbness or dysesthesias in 1st - 4th digits. sx exacerbated during sleep (most common sx) and relieved with wrist shaking",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710207455\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: continuous sensory deficits in the median nerve distribution, involving the entire palm and radiating proximally. ability to handle fine objects is impaired",\n                answer: "**Moderate CTS::CTS severity**: continuous sensory deficits in the median nerve distribution, involving the entire palm and radiating proximally. ability to handle fine objects is impaired",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710297488\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: sensory loss and thenar muscular atrophy",\n                answer: "**Severe CTS::CTS severity**: sensory loss and thenar muscular atrophy",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710333408\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS etiologyobesitydiabetes[...][...][...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "CTS etiologyobesitydiabetes**thyroid disease****RA tenosynovitis****CHF****renal failure****mass (tumor, hematoma)****pregnancy**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710466838\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS treatments (conserative)[...][...] [...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "CTS treatments (conserative)**Ergonomic modification****hand splint** **NSAIDs****steroid injection****diuretics****vitamin B6**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710635957\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS treatmentOrthotics: Hand splint neutral to [...]-degree extension",\n                answer: "CTS treatmentOrthotics: Hand splint neutral to **30**-degree extension",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645710741702\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS surgical indicationsx's of numbness/paresthesias, severe pain despite [...]",\n                answer: "CTS surgical indicationsx's of numbness/paresthesias, severe pain despite **a trial of conservative treatment::modifier**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645711632016\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with...Symptoms >[...] months in durationPositive Phalen’s test in <[...] secondsany [...]any [...]",\n                answer: "CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with...Symptoms >**10 ** months in durationPositive Phalen’s test in <**10** secondsany **mod-severe clinical sx's**any **mod-severe EDX findings**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645711830241\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] aka [...] or [...] may exclusively affect the [...]",\n                answer: "**Neuralgic amyotrophy** aka **Parsonage-Turner Syndrome** or **idiopathic brachial plexopathy** may exclusively affect the **anterior interosseous nerve (AIN)::nerve**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645714383502\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Clinically, (sx's) Sensory deficits in the [...] can help to differentiate a proximal median neuropathy from CTS",\n                answer: "Clinically, (sx's) Sensory deficits in the **palm / thenar eminence** can help to differentiate a proximal median neuropathy from CTS",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1645714594415\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NCS of demeylinating injuries Amplitude typically normal: but may be decreased due to... [...] and [...] or [...]",\n                answer: "NCS of demeylinating injuries Amplitude typically normal: but may be decreased due to... **temporal dispersion** and **phase-cancellation** or **conduction block**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646357253567\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: median to ulnar nerve “crossover” in the mid-forearm that involves [...] fibers most common, occurring in about [...] of median nerves",\n                answer: "**Martin-Gruber anastomosis**: median to ulnar nerve “crossover” in the mid-forearm that involves **motor** fibers most common, occurring in about **1/3** of median nerves",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646436858242\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Martin-Gruber anastamosis, Median n. now innervates...[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Martin-Gruber anastamosis, Median n. now innervates...**adductor pollicis (ADP)****abductor digiti minimi (ADM)****first dorsal interossei (FDI)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646437038540\n            },\n            {\n                question: "When present, the MGA can lead to unusual sparing of muscles after severe proximal [...] nerve injury or [...] distally",\n                answer: "When present, the MGA can lead to unusual sparing of muscles after severe proximal **ulnar** nerve injury or **CTS::diagnosis** distally",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646437145133\n            },\n            {\n                question: "a proximal [...] nerve injury can lead to unexpectedly widespread denervation in the presence of the MGA",\n                answer: "a proximal **median** nerve injury can lead to unexpectedly widespread denervation in the presence of the MGA",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646437197923\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MGA can be recognized by a Median n. CMAP that is larger w/ stim. at the [...] than at the [...] In such cases, obtain the [...] CMAP from the [...]...this will be smaller with stimulation at the [...] compared with the [...]",\n                answer: "MGA can be recognized by a Median n. CMAP that is larger w/ stim. at the **elbow** than at the **wrist** In such cases, obtain the **Ulnar n.** CMAP from the **APB**...this will be smaller with stimulation at the **elbow** compared with the **wrist**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646437507271\n            },\n            {\n                question: "in MGA An initial [...] deflection of the median nerve CMAP at [...] is seen,which is not seen at the [...]. Only seen with concomitant [...]",\n                answer: "in MGA An initial **positive** deflection of the median nerve CMAP at **elbow** is seen,which is not seen at the **wrist**. Only seen with concomitant **CTS**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646437688988\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In MGA one can see an artificially [...] this is 2/2 an unreasonably small [...]",\n                answer: "In MGA one can see an artificially **fast CV::increased/decreased, parameter** this is 2/2 an unreasonably small **latency difference**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646438490416\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]connection of the [...] median nerve to the [...] ulnar nerve",\n                answer: "**RICHE-CANNIEU ANASTOMOSIS**connection of the **recurrent branch of the::specific part** median nerve to the **deep motor branch of the::specific part** ulnar nerve",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646438561156\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Riche-cannieuWhile recording over the APB muscle, CMAP is absent with [...] nerve stimulation but present with stimulation of the [...] nerve",\n                answer: "Riche-cannieuWhile recording over the APB muscle, CMAP is absent with **median** nerve stimulation but present with stimulation of the **ulnar** nerve",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646438605744\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG phases equal the [...]Normally, motor unit potentials have [...] or fewer phases",\n                answer: "EMG phases equal the **# of BL crossings +1**Normally, motor unit potentials have **4** or fewer phases",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1646683692695\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar N. Course descends along the medial surface of the [...]. It runs within fascia known as the [...]. between the medial epicondyle and olecranon called the [...] enters the forearm through an aponeuroosis aka the [...] joining the two heads of the [...] At the wrist, beween the [...] called Guyon’s canal",\n                answer: "Ulnar N. Course descends along the medial surface of the **medial head triceps**. It runs within fascia known as the **arcade of Struthers (AOS)**. between the medial epicondyle and olecranon called the **retrocondylar groove** enters the forearm through an aponeuroosis aka the **cubital tunnel** joining the two heads of the **flexor carpi ulnaris** At the wrist, beween the **pisiform and hamate::2** called Guyon’s canal",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647103466552\n            },\n            {\n                question: "through Guyon’s canal, Ulnar n. splits into 3 branches1. [...]2. [...]3. [...]",\n                answer: "through Guyon’s canal, Ulnar n. splits into 3 branches1. **Superficial sensory branch**2. **Hypothenar branch**3. **Deep motor branch**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647103617784\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar N Hypothenar branch innervated 3 muscles[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Ulnar N Hypothenar branch innervated 3 muscles**Opponens digiti quinti****Abductor digiti quinti****Flexor digiti quinti**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647103877894\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar N. Deep motor branch innervates m.:[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Ulnar N. Deep motor branch innervates m.:**Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)****Adductor pollicis****Interossei (Palmar and Dorsal)****Lumbricals (4th & 5th)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647104276650\n            },\n            {\n                question: "The Ulnar n. aka \"1-1/2\" Nerve1-1/2 muscle of the forearm[...][...]1-1/2 muscles of the thumb[...][...]1-1/2 muscle class of the palm*[...][...]",\n                answer: "The Ulnar n. aka \"1-1/2\" Nerve1-1/2 muscle of the forearm**1 Flexor carpi ulnaris****1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4)**1-1/2 muscles of the thumb**1 Adductor pollicis****1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)**1-1/2 muscle class of the palm***1 Interosse (all)****1/2 lumbricals (3, 4)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647104569842\n            },\n            {\n                question: "About the middle of the forearm, the Ulnar n. gives rise to the [...] branch,provides sensory innervation to the [...].",\n                answer: "About the middle of the forearm, the Ulnar n. gives rise to the **ulnar palmar cutaneous** branch,provides sensory innervation to the **proximal hypothenar (medial palm) area**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647104786183\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] nerve: arising 8 cm proximal to [...]",\n                answer: "**Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC)** nerve: arising 8 cm proximal to **Guyon’s canal**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647104944884\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC) nerve: normal or abnormalNCS are [...] in a handle-bar neuropathy at the wrist but [...] in more proximal compressions ie. CUTS",\n                answer: "Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC) nerve: normal or abnormalNCS are **normal** in a handle-bar neuropathy at the wrist but **abnormal** in more proximal compressions ie. CUTS",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647105191122\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the [...] to the [...]pt demonstrates involvement of [...]Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in [...]",\n                answer: "**ARCADE OF STRUTHERS**: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the **brachialis** to the **triceps brachii-medial**pt demonstrates involvement of **all ulnar nerve innervated muscles and sensory**Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in **radial deviation**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647110795565\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... [...]: unopposed [...] causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the [...] joints",\n                answer: "Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... **Ulnar claw hand**: unopposed **extensor digitorum communis (EDC)** causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the **MCP** joints",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647111040570\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] sign: inability to hold a paper by pure thumb [...] weakness). pt substitutes [...] muscle, causing flexion of the DlP joint",\n                answer: "**Froment’s** sign: inability to hold a paper by pure thumb **adduction (adductor pollicis::action/muscle** weakness). pt substitutes **FPL** muscle, causing flexion of the DlP joint",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647111366937\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] sign: Inability to adduct the [...] weakness)",\n                answer: "**Wartenberg’s** sign: Inability to adduct the **5th digit (palmar interossei::body part/muscle** weakness)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647111553994\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracturepresents same as [...] syndrome",\n                answer: "**TARDY ULNAR NERVE PALSY** a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracturepresents same as **arcade of struthers** syndrome",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647112052561\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings..SNAP: Abnormal [...] findings (if severe)CMAP: abnormal [...] (in conduction block)CMAP: normal [...] (in conduction block)Approximately [...] msec decrease in [...] or a [...] drop in amplitude",\n                answer: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings..SNAP: Abnormal **sup. sensory (5th digit) & DUC** findings (if severe)CMAP: abnormal **above elbow::site** (in conduction block)CMAP: normal **wrist and B. elbow sites::site** (in conduction block)Approximately **10 - 15::2# range** msec decrease in **CV** or a **20%** drop in amplitude",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647112847952\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar GrooveNCS: [...] conduction studies are most usefultypically become abnormal 1st 2/2 [...] organization",\n                answer: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar GrooveNCS: **Motor::sensory / motor** conduction studies are most usefultypically become abnormal 1st 2/2 **somatotopic** organization",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647113097463\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Cubital tunnel syndrome v.s. Retro Condylar Groove entrapmentmuscles involved include all ulnar n. innervated m’sSave for the [...], which may or may not be involved",\n                answer: "Cubital tunnel syndrome v.s. Retro Condylar Groove entrapmentmuscles involved include all ulnar n. innervated m’sSave for the **FCU**, which may or may not be involved",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647113269072\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDX findings...EMG: abnormal activity in hand intrinsics [...] forearm muscles",\n                answer: "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDX findings...EMG: abnormal activity in hand intrinsics **>::</=/> ** forearm muscles",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647113458907\n            },\n            {\n                question: "GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation(1) [...] (2) [...] (3) [...](4) [...]",\n                answer: "GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation(1) **deep palmar motor** (2) **deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor** (3) **evrything (proximal canal lesion)**(4) **only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647114332678\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Guyons Canal EDX findings...SNAP: [...]CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal [...] (in conduction block)CV: [...] at the above elbow siteEMG: Abnormal activity in [...]",\n                answer: "Guyons Canal EDX findings...SNAP: **5th digit is abnormal, but DUC is normal**CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal **Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp)::site** (in conduction block)CV: **normal::normal/abnormal** at the above elbow siteEMG: Abnormal activity in **ulnar innervated hand m's**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647114682410\n            },\n            {\n                question: "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the [...]this is important* as the former requires [...]",\n                answer: "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the **inching technique**this is important* as the former requires **nerve transposition**",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647118306827\n            },\n            {\n                question: "the most common cause of peripheral neuropathy wordlwide is [...]",\n                answer: "the most common cause of peripheral neuropathy wordlwide is **leprosy**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647271368888\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In conduction block, EMG may reveal [...]",\n                answer: "In conduction block, EMG may reveal **decreased recruitment**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647566744208\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Conduction Block To be considered significant, the drop in proximal amplitude should be more than [...]% of the distal amplitude.",\n                answer: "Conduction Block To be considered significant, the drop in proximal amplitude should be more than **20**% of the distal amplitude.",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647566980413\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Nerve conduction studies in [...] [...] difference estimates the amount of [...] Usually, a [...]% difference is considered significantRecall that a significant drop in amp should be associated with [...]",\n                answer: "Nerve conduction studies in **axonal injuries::pathology** **side-to-side** difference estimates the amount of **axonal loss::same as 1** Usually, a **50**% difference is considered significantRecall that a significant drop in amp should be associated with **spontaneous activity**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647567132850\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axonal Injury Latencies and conduction velocities should [...] affected.",\n                answer: "Axonal Injury Latencies and conduction velocities should **not be::be/not be** affected.",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647567326433\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axonal Injury If [...] is present, the CMAP or SNAP amplitude will be unobtainable both proximal and distal to the lesion",\n                answer: "Axonal Injury If **neurotmesis::sunderland** is present, the CMAP or SNAP amplitude will be unobtainable both proximal and distal to the lesion",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647567351542\n            },\n            {\n                question: "4 Median n. FOREARM muscles(non-AIN m's)[...] [...][...][...]",\n                answer: "4 Median n. FOREARM muscles(non-AIN m's)**Pronator teres** **FCR****Palmaris longus****Flexor digitorum superficialis**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1647819065544\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axonal Injury[...] and [...] should NOT be affectedUnless the [...] are affected",\n                answer: "Axonal Injury**O/P Latency** and **CV** should NOT be affectedUnless the **largest/fastest fibers::2** are affected",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648316037027\n            },\n            {\n                question: "sensory loss in the forearm or arm [...] a feature of an ulnar nerve lesion",\n                answer: "sensory loss in the forearm or arm **is not::is / is not** a feature of an ulnar nerve lesion",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648316417976\n            },\n            {\n                question: "“Clawing”—seen best with [...] lesions of median or ulnar nerves. Remaining extrinsic m. eg. [...] exaggerates the loss of the [...]",\n                answer: "“Clawing”—seen best with **distal** lesions of median or ulnar nerves. Remaining extrinsic m. eg. **flexor digitourm profundus** exaggerates the loss of the **lumbricals**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648316962748\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Distortions of the hand median or ulnar n. Deficits less pronounced in [...] lesions; deficits present during [...]",\n                answer: "Distortions of the hand median or ulnar n. Deficits less pronounced in **proximal::distal/proximal** lesions; deficits present during **flexion::rest/flexion**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648317080437\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar Motor study (ADM) MGA can be recognized...by a CMAP that is smaller with stimulation of the ulnar nerve at the [...] site than at the [...] siteproduces a [...] in the forearm (Preston and Shapiro, 2005)",\n                answer: "Ulnar Motor study (ADM) MGA can be recognized...by a CMAP that is smaller with stimulation of the ulnar nerve at the **B/A elbow** site than at the **wrist** siteproduces a **“pseudo-conduction block”** in the forearm (Preston and Shapiro, 2005)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648319545747\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ulnar Motor study MGA can be recognized...usually more apparent when recording from the [...] muscle, than [...] In such cases, the CMAP from the [...] muscle will be...[...] with stimulation of the median n. at the [...] compared the [...]",\n                answer: "Ulnar Motor study MGA can be recognized...usually more apparent when recording from the **FDI::site 1** muscle, than **ADM::site 2** In such cases, the CMAP from the **FDI::site 1** muscle will be...**larger** with stimulation of the median n. at the **elbow** compared the **wrist**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648319999826\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Riches-Cannieu anastomosis (RCA) anastomosis in the [...] between the [...] and [...] severe [...] nerve injury in the arm = weak forearm flexors & sparing of thenar muscles. severe [...] nerve injury in the arm = unexpected weakness of all intrinsic hand muscles (including thenar)",\n                answer: "Riches-Cannieu anastomosis (RCA) anastomosis in the **palm** between the **ulnar deep motor branch** and **re-current median branch** severe **median** nerve injury in the arm = weak forearm flexors & sparing of thenar muscles. severe **ulnar** nerve injury in the arm = unexpected weakness of all intrinsic hand muscles (including thenar)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648320761994\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Median Motor study (APB) suspect RCA if CMAP...[...] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: reduced or absent[...] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: present",\n                answer: "Median Motor study (APB) suspect RCA if CMAP...**median** n. stim at the wrist/elbow: reduced or absent**ulnar** n. stim at the wrist/elbow: present",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648321231503\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radial n. course[...] to the axillary artery. then, through the [...] (boarders made up of)under the [...] and between the [...] musclesalong the [...] before entering the anterior compartmentdescends between [...] medialy and [...] lateraly[...] to the [...] the n. branches into the [...] and [...] in the forearm it passes between superficial and deep heads of the [...] muscle aka the [...]",\n                answer: "Radial n. course**posterior** to the axillary artery. then, through the **triangular interval** (boarders made up of)under the **teres major** and between the **Lateral & Medial triceps::2** musclesalong the **spiral groove** before entering the anterior compartmentdescends between **brachialis** medialy and **brachioradialis** lateraly**anterior** to the **lateral epicondyle** the n. branches into the **PIN** and **superficial radial** in the forearm it passes between superficial and deep heads of the **supinator** muscle aka the **arcade of Fröhse**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648385475248\n            },\n            {\n                question: "radial nerve cutaneous distributioninnervated above the spiral groove- [...]- [...]innervated below the spiral groove- [...]- [...]",\n                answer: "radial nerve cutaneous distributioninnervated above the spiral groove- **posterior cutaneous nerve of the arm**- **inferior lateral cutaneous nerve of the arm**innervated below the spiral groove- **posterior cutaneous nerve of forearm**- **superficial branch**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648385937276\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radial N. muscles of the armMuscles innervated above the spiral groove:[...][...]Muscles innervated below the spiral groove:[...][...]+/- [...]",\n                answer: "Radial N. muscles of the armMuscles innervated above the spiral groove:**Triceps brachii****Anconeus**Muscles innervated below the spiral groove:**Brachioradialis****ECR-L**+/- **ECR-B**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648386285281\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearmSuperficial [...][...][...][...]Deep/Snuff box muscles [...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearmSuperficial **Supinator****Extensor digitorum (communus)****Extensor digiti minimi (EDM)****Extensor carpi ulnaris (ECU)**Deep/Snuff box muscles **Abductor pollicis longus (APL)****Extensor pollicis longus (EPL)****Extensor pollicis brevis (EPB)****Extensor indicis proprius (EIP)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648386541230\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the [...] of the brachial plexus (rare)",\n                answer: "**CRUTCH PALSY** aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the **posterior cord** of the brachial plexus (rare)",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648386963408\n            },\n            {\n                question: "crutch palsy clincial presentationmay c/o weakness in [...], Sensation may be decreased over the [...]",\n                answer: "crutch palsy clincial presentationmay c/o weakness in **all radial n. innervated m.**, Sensation may be decreased over the **posterior arm, forearm, and hand**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648387116390\n            },\n            {\n                question: "crutch palsy EDX findings CMAP Cases associated with axonal loss and Wallerian degeneration show [...] at [...]Cases associated with meylin loss and Conduction block show [...] at [...] SNAP [...] response is [...] in cases of axonal loss EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",\n                answer: "crutch palsy EDX findings CMAP Cases associated with axonal loss and Wallerian degeneration show **low amplitudes** at **all 3 stim sites**Cases associated with meylin loss and Conduction block show **Nl. amplitudes** at **all 3 stim sites** SNAP **superficial radial sensory** response is **reduced in amplitude/absent** in cases of axonal loss EMGAbnormal activity in **all radial n. muscles +/- posterior cord muscles::2 categories**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648387496494\n            },\n            {\n                question: "radial n. Injury at the spiral-groove is also known as [...] palsy or [...] palsy",\n                answer: "radial n. Injury at the spiral-groove is also known as **Saturday night** palsy or **honeymooner’s** palsy",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648387570248\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radial n. injury at spiral-grooveclinical presentationweakness of [...], [...], [...], and [...]There is preservation of [...] Sensory deficits may occur in the [...]",\n                answer: "Radial n. injury at spiral-grooveclinical presentationweakness of **elbow flexion (BR)**, **supination**, **wrist extension (ECR-L/B, ECU)**, and **finger extension (EDC)**There is preservation of **elbow extension (triceps, anconeus)** Sensory deficits may occur in the **dorsal aspect hand and forearm**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648387937920\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings:NCS:CMAP: normal at [...] in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at [...] in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be [...] in [...]EMG: Abnormal activity in [...]",\n                answer: "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings:NCS:CMAP: normal at **all 3 sites::stim site** in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at **all 3 sites::stim site** in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be **normal** in **demyelination**EMG: Abnormal activity in **all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus::m.**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648388439389\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Differential Diagnosis of a Wrist Drop[...][...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Differential Diagnosis of a Wrist Drop**Central: SCI/TBI/CVA, etc.****Radiculopathy: C6 or C7::2****Plexopathy: Posterior cord, upper / middle trunk::3****Mononeuropathy: PIN, radial nerve::2****Diffuse polyneuropathy: Lead**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648388620818\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] radial nerve can be entrapped between the [...]c/o [...] pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic [...]",\n                answer: "**RADIAL TUNNEL SYNDROME** radial nerve can be entrapped between the **brachialis and BR::2**c/o **lateral/dorsal proximal forearm** pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic **lateral epicondylitis**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648388915714\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radial Tunnel syndrome NCS will demonstrate [...] EMG will demonstrate [...]",\n                answer: "Radial Tunnel syndrome NCS will demonstrate **typically no findings** EMG will demonstrate **typically no findings**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648389241764\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: radial n. injured at the [...] of the supinatorpresents with [...] weakness of all the [...]they will display weakness with only [...] and will show a [...] deviated wrist",\n                answer: "**posterior interosseous syndrome**: radial n. injured at the **Arcade of Frohse** of the supinatorpresents with **painless*::painful/painless** weakness of all the **PIN innervated m::same**they will display weakness with only **finger/thumb extension::2** and will show a **radial (ECU weak. ECR intact)** deviated wrist",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648390000301\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Posterior interosseous syndrome EDX findings:NCS: superfical radial sensory [...] SNAP. in conduction block [...] radial CMAP when recording over PIN innervated muscles (EIP)EMG:Abnormal in +/- supinator and all PIN muscles.[...] are always spared",\n                answer: "Posterior interosseous syndrome EDX findings:NCS: superfical radial sensory **Normal::normal/abnormal** SNAP. in conduction block **Abnormal::normal/abnormal** radial CMAP when recording over PIN innervated muscles (EIP)EMG:Abnormal in +/- supinator and all PIN muscles.**triceps, anconeus, BR, ECR-L, and ECR-B::5** are always spared",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1648390658768\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Superficial radial neuropathy: also known as [...] or [...] also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy",\n                answer: "Superficial radial neuropathy: also known as **Wartenberg syndrome::eponym** or **cheiralgia paresthetica** also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1649363201236\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Hand-cuff palsy EDX findings: Normal/AbnormalNCS: superfical radial nerve SNAP: [...] radial nerve CMAP: [...] EMG: [...]",\n                answer: "Hand-cuff palsy EDX findings: Normal/AbnormalNCS: superfical radial nerve SNAP: **Abnormal** radial nerve CMAP: **Normal** EMG: **Normal**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1649363528230\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located proximal to the DRGCMAP: [...]",\n                answer: "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located proximal to the DRGCMAP: **Normal or reduced amplitude::2**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1649365335683\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Note that a mean of [...]-waves can be used as a surrogate for one H-reflex",\n                answer: "Note that a mean of **10 F**-waves can be used as a surrogate for one H-reflex",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1649688608541\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Musculocutaneous n. course arises from the lateral cord of the brachial plexus near the lower border of [...] muscle. downward to pierce the [...] muscle, which it innervates. in the upper arm, travels between the [...] muscles at the antecubital fossa, it pierces deep fascia lateral to the [...] and becomes the LAC",\n                answer: "Musculocutaneous n. course arises from the lateral cord of the brachial plexus near the lower border of **pectoralis minor** muscle. downward to pierce the **coracobrachialis** muscle, which it innervates. in the upper arm, travels between the **brachialis and biceps::2** muscles at the antecubital fossa, it pierces deep fascia lateral to the **biceps tendon** and becomes the LAC",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650035365488\n            },\n            {\n                question: "musculocutaneous nerve. innervates ARM 3 muscles [...][...][...]FOREARM 1 cutaneous sensory [...]",\n                answer: "musculocutaneous nerve. innervates ARM 3 muscles **Coracobrachialis****Biceps brachii****Brachialis (also radial nerve)**FOREARM 1 cutaneous sensory **lateral antebrachial cutaneous (LAC)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650035649219\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MUSCULOCUTANEOUS MONO-NEUROPATHYIn General: Injury to the [...] portion of the nerve is more common than to the [...] portion",\n                answer: "MUSCULOCUTANEOUS MONO-NEUROPATHYIn General: Injury to the **distal::proximal/distal** portion of the nerve is more common than to the **proximal::proximal/distal** portion",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650036460113\n            },\n            {\n                question: "{{c1::median SNAP {from the thumb} and superficial radial SNAP::2 EDx}} should be performed to distinguish musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy from upper trunk lesion",\n                answer: "{{c1::median SNAP {from the thumb} and superficial radial SNAP::2 EDx}} should be performed to distinguish musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy from upper trunk lesion",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "definition",\n                id: 1650036632531\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy clinical pres. patient may complain of [...] weakness and abnormal sensation over the [...]",\n                answer: "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy clinical pres. patient may complain of **elbow flexion** weakness and abnormal sensation over the **lateral forearm**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650036756464\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal SNAP in the [...]Abnormal CMAP to the [...]EMG:Abnormal activity in the [...]",\n                answer: "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal SNAP in the **LAC**Abnormal CMAP to the **biceps brachii**EMG:Abnormal activity in the **biceps brachii**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650037069663\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axillary n. Course: descends posterior to the [...] artery and anterior to the [...] muscle. it then curves posteriorly through the [...] with the posterior circumflex artery. As the nerve emerges, it divides into anterior and posterior terminal divisions.",\n                answer: "Axillary n. Course: descends posterior to the **axillary** artery and anterior to the **subscapularis** muscle. it then curves posteriorly through the **quadrangular space** with the posterior circumflex artery. As the nerve emerges, it divides into anterior and posterior terminal divisions.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650038357953\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axillary n. innervates 3 [...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Axillary n. innervates 3 **Teres minor****Deltoid****Upper lateral cutaneous nerve::sensory**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650038451864\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings:NCS:SNAP [...]CMAP: [...] EMG:Abnormal activity in the [...] muscles",\n                answer: "Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings:NCS:SNAP **not available**CMAP: **Abnormal (not done)** EMG:Abnormal activity in the **deltoid and teres minor::2** muscles",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650038778690\n            },\n            {\n                question: "suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the [...] which it branches off then passes the [...] of the neck and runs beneath the [...] to the superior margin of the scapula.It runs through the [...], to innervate the [...] The nerve then wraps around the [...], to innervate the [...]",\n                answer: "suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the **upper trunk::plexus** which it branches off then passes the **posterior triangle** of the neck and runs beneath the **trapezius** to the superior margin of the scapula.It runs through the **suprascapular notch**, to innervate the **supraspinatus** The nerve then wraps around the **spinoglenoid notch**, to innervate the **infraspinatus**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650039428954\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHYThis is the only peripheral nerve injury at the [...] level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in [...]",\n                answer: "SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHYThis is the only peripheral nerve injury at the **trunk** level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in **neuralgic amyotrophy**",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650039617011\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Suprascapular neuropathy clinical pres.proximal injury results in weakness in both [...] and [...] Nerve injury at the spinoglenoid notch will result in weakness [...]",\n                answer: "Suprascapular neuropathy clinical pres.proximal injury results in weakness in both **shoulder abduction (SS)** and **external rotation (IS)** Nerve injury at the spinoglenoid notch will result in weakness **only in external rotation (IS)**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650039841620\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Long thoracic n.runs distally along the thoracic wall to innervate the [...]",\n                answer: "Long thoracic n.runs distally along the thoracic wall to innervate the **serratus anterior**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650040083342\n            },\n            {\n                question: "2 main types of shoulder winging. EDx findings...Medial winging: EMG findings in [...] Lateral winging: EMG findings in [...]",\n                answer: "2 main types of shoulder winging. EDx findings...Medial winging: EMG findings in **serratus anterior** Lateral winging: EMG findings in **trapezius (&SCM)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650040439910\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Treatment of serratus anterior injury/injury to the long thoracic nerve: same 2 for both(a) acute stage, pain reduction and ROM exercise; (b) intermediate stage, passive stretching of the [...], [...], and pectoralis minor; (c) late stage, strengthening exercise of all shoulder girdle muscles, including the trapezius.Treatment of trapezius palsy/injury to the spinal accessory nerve: Will involve physical therapy to adequately strengthen adjacent muscle groups, including [...] and [...].Surgic...",\n                answer: "Treatment of serratus anterior injury/injury to the long thoracic nerve: same 2 for both(a) acute stage, pain reduction and ROM exercise; (b) intermediate stage, passive stretching of the **rhomboids**, **levator scapulae**, and pectoralis minor; (c) late stage, strengthening exercise of all shoulder girdle muscles, including the trapezius.Treatment of trapezius palsy/injury to the spinal accessory nerve: Will involve physical therapy to adequately strengthen adjacent muscle groups, including **rhomboids** and **levator scapulae**.Surgical repair with a **dynamic muscle transfer** is recommended if the patient fails conservative treatment.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1650040991808\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor unit [...] is a better measure of pathology",\n                answer: "Motor unit **duration::polyphasicity/duration** is a better measure of pathology",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1651175503251\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Abnormal spontaneous potentials are usually only found in [...]",\n                answer: "Abnormal spontaneous potentials are usually only found in **axonal injury::axon/myelin injury**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1651175806279\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] injury may generate spontaneous activity",\n                answer: "**BOTH Muscle & Nerve::muscle/nerve** injury may generate spontaneous activity",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1654356207919\n            },\n            {\n                question: "lateral femoral cutaneous n.pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the [...] and [...] nerve roots from the [...] division of the lumbar plexus",\n                answer: "lateral femoral cutaneous n.pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the **L2** and **L3** nerve roots from the **posterior** division of the lumbar plexus",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657459282046\n            },\n            {\n                question: "lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka [...]Etiology1.) [...]2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, [...], infection, [...] 3.) [...]",\n                answer: "lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka **meralgia paresthetica**Etiology1.) **compression**2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, **tumor**, infection, **weight gain/loss** 3.) **Iatrogenic::category**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657459774010\n            },\n            {\n                question: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the [...] toward the [...]It passes underneath the [...] to provide sensation to the lateral thigh",\n                answer: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the **iliacus::m.** toward the **anterior iliac spine**It passes underneath the **inguinal ligament** to provide sensation to the lateral thigh",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657460002285\n            },\n            {\n                question: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve. clinical pres.patient may report sensory complaints in the lateral thigh, including pain, numbness, burning, or a dull ache, exacerbated by [...] and [...]",\n                answer: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve. clinical pres.patient may report sensory complaints in the lateral thigh, including pain, numbness, burning, or a dull ache, exacerbated by **hip extension/flexion** and **prolonged sitting**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657460214376\n            },\n            {\n                question: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...] CMAP: [...]EMG[...]",\n                answer: "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal lateral femoral cutaneous nerve (not typically done)** CMAP: **not available**EMG**not available**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657460357643\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Femoral n. innervates (motor)[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Femoral n. innervates (motor)**Iliacus* (illiopsoas)****Pectineus (1/2)****Sartorius****Quadriceps m. x4::category**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657461725787\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sensory Femoral n. innervates Iliacus (illiopsoas)Pectineus (1/2)Anterior BranchSartorius[...][...]Posterior Branch[...][...]Quadriceps m. x4",\n                answer: "Sensory Femoral n. innervates Iliacus (illiopsoas)Pectineus (1/2)Anterior BranchSartorius**intermediate cutaneous nerve of the thigh::Sensory****medial cutaneous nerve of the thigh::Sensory**Posterior Branch**Saphenous nerve::Sensory****infra-patellar branch of saphenous::Sensory**Quadriceps m. x4",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657462196164\n            },\n            {\n                question: "FEMORAL NERVE course: lumbar plexus, 2, 3, 4 ventral rami. within the substance of the [...]. emerges in a groove between this muscle and the [...] and descends under the [...] beneath which, a branch courses behind the [...] to innervate the [...]in the [...], n. lies on the iliacus m. lateral to the [...]About [...] cm distal, it divides into 2 cutaneous n's The [...] divides to the sartorius and two cutaneous branches (intermediate and medial cutaneous n's of thigh) The [...] divides into ...",\n                answer: "FEMORAL NERVE course: lumbar plexus, 2, 3, 4 ventral rami. within the substance of the **psoas major**. emerges in a groove between this muscle and the **iliacus** and descends under the **inguinal ligament** beneath which, a branch courses behind the **femoral sheath** to innervate the **pectineus m.**in the **femoral triangle**, n. lies on the iliacus m. lateral to the **femoral artery**About **4** cm distal, it divides into 2 cutaneous n's The **anterior division** divides to the sartorius and two cutaneous branches (intermediate and medial cutaneous n's of thigh) The **posterior division** divides into the saphenous branch and rectus branches",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657463547131\n            },\n            {\n                question: "saphenous nerve course, a [...] nerve femoral n --> [...] division --> saphenous n. travels through the [...]descends to the [...], where it becomes [...], and joins the saphenous v.provides sensation to the skin of the [...]",\n                answer: "saphenous nerve course, a **pure sensory::motor/sensory/mixed** nerve femoral n --> **posterior** division --> saphenous n. travels through the **adductor canal**descends to the **knee**, where it becomes **subcutaneous**, and joins the saphenous v.provides sensation to the skin of the **medial leg, ankle, and foot::3**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657464883811\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Femoral Neuropathy, Etiology:compression/trauma [...] tumor entrapped at inguinal ligamentfractureiatrogenic (most common)[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Femoral Neuropathy, Etiology:compression/trauma **retroperitoneal hemmorhage/ psoas hematoma::2** tumor entrapped at inguinal ligamentfractureiatrogenic (most common)**positioning during surgery (eg. dorsal lithotomy)****cardiac catherization****THA****femoral/inguinal hernia repair**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657466031956\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Femoral Neuropathyclinical presentation:patient may complain of weakness of [...][...] weakness is noted with injuries occurring above the [...]decreased sensation over the [...], [...], and [...] [...] reflex is reduced or absent",\n                answer: "Femoral Neuropathyclinical presentation:patient may complain of weakness of **knee extension****Hip flexion** weakness is noted with injuries occurring above the **inguinal ligament**decreased sensation over the **anterior thigh**, **medial thigh**, and **medial leg** **patellar tendon** reflex is reduced or absent",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657466279957\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal [...]Abnormal [...]EMG:- Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. [...]) to r/o [...] involvement",\n                answer: "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal **saphenous nerve SNAP**Abnormal **rectus femoris CMAP**EMG:- Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. **hamstrings, gluts, adductor::1ex.**) to r/o **plexus/root::2** involvement",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657466862912\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is the most common cause of femoral neuropathy",\n                answer: "**Diabetic amyotrophy** is the most common cause of femoral neuropathy",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657467106448\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathiesit is also known as a [...] neuropathy",\n                answer: "**Diabetic amyotrophy** is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathiesit is also known as a **lumbo-sacral radiculo-plexus::\"4-names\"** neuropathy",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657467185148\n            },\n            {\n                question: "exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal [...]. The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting [...] injury and perivascular infiltrateamyotrophy has been noted to occur after [...]",\n                answer: "exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal **immune-mediated microvasculitis::2 names**. The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting **ischemic** injury and perivascular infiltrateamyotrophy has been noted to occur after **marked weight loss::pt characteristic**",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657467276166\n            },\n            {\n                question: "diabetic amyotrophy typically affects (epidimiology)[...]usually [...][...]",\n                answer: "diabetic amyotrophy typically affects (epidimiology)**males**usually **> 50 yo****type 2 DM**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657468292088\n            },\n            {\n                question: "diabetic amyotrophyClinical presentation:begins with [...] in the [...] or [...]commonly spreads to the [...] within [...] Patients then develops [...] and [...] of the proximal > distal lower extremity musculature",\n                answer: "diabetic amyotrophyClinical presentation:begins with **severe unilateral pain** in the **lumbar region** or **proximal lower extremity**commonly spreads to the **contralateral side** within **weeks to months::time range** Patients then develops **weakness** and **atrophy** of the proximal > distal lower extremity musculature",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657468621213\n            },\n            {\n                question: "diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings:NCS:[...] SNAP saphenous*[...] CMAP rectusEMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), [...]iliopsoas[...]",\n                answer: "diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings:NCS:**Abnormal** SNAP saphenous***Abnormal** CMAP rectusEMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), **adductors**iliopsoas**paraspinals**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657468787620\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHYEtiologycan be entrapped in the [...] (aka [...]) or between the [...] and [...]iatrogenic trauma, including [...] or [...]",\n                answer: "SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHYEtiologycan be entrapped in the **hip adductor canal** (aka **Hunter’s canal**) or between the **sartorius** and **gracilis**iatrogenic trauma, including **knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy** or **catheterization/thrombectomy**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657976050421\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Saphenous Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...] EMGfemoral nerve innervated muscles: [...]",\n                answer: "Saphenous Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal saphenous nerve**CMAP: **Normal** EMGfemoral nerve innervated muscles: **Normal**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657976454410\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the [...], and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral ramiexits the pelvis through the [...] below the [...] musclebetween the [...] and [...]. (bony landmarks)the nerve is deep to the [...] m. and [...] m.down the midline of the thigh closely related to the [...]travels as one unit up to the [...], where it splits into the peroneal (fibular) division and tibial division",\n                answer: "Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the **lumbosacral trunk**, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral ramiexits the pelvis through the **greater sciatic foramen** below the **piriformis** musclebetween the **lesser trochanter** and **ischial tuberosity**. (bony landmarks)the nerve is deep to the **gluteus maximus::pelvis** m. and **biceps femoris::thigh** m.down the midline of the thigh closely related to the **shaft of the femur**travels as one unit up to the **popliteal fossa**, where it splits into the peroneal (fibular) division and tibial division",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657978130178\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sciatic nerve muscle innervation in the thighperoneal (fibular) division [...]tibial division [...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Sciatic nerve muscle innervation in the thighperoneal (fibular) division **Short head biceps femoris**tibial division **Long head biceps femoris****Semitendinosus****Semimembranosus****Adductor magnus (also obturator n.)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657978403942\n            },\n            {\n                question: "the [...] division makes up the outer two-thirds of the sciatic nerve proper",\n                answer: "the **peroneal** division makes up the outer two-thirds of the sciatic nerve proper",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657978722014\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SCIATIC NEUROPATHYEtiology:[...][...][...]hematoma / tumor penetrating woundsgravid uterus",\n                answer: "SCIATIC NEUROPATHYEtiology:**hip dislocation / fx****THA****IM injection**hematoma / tumor penetrating woundsgravid uterus",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657978979780\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the [...] portion of the nerve",\n                answer: "**Piriformis syndrome** is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the **peroneal (fibular)** portion of the nerve",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657979081889\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sciatic neuropathyClinical presentation:primarily presents as weakness of [...] and [...]numbness occurs over the [...] and the [...]The [...] and [...] may be abnormal (physical examination)",\n                answer: "Sciatic neuropathyClinical presentation:primarily presents as weakness of **knee flexion** and **muscles of the peroneal (foot drop) and tibial nerves* (plantar flexion)**numbness occurs over the **lateral leg** and the **entire foot**The **lateral hamstring** and **Achilles reflexes** may be abnormal (physical examination)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657983199640\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...] CMAP: Abnormal [...] EMGAbnormal activity in [...]Normal activity in [...] and [...] absent or delayed [...]",\n                answer: "Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal ** superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory** CMAP: Abnormal **tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies** EMGAbnormal activity in **all sciatic innervated musculature 1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t), 2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and 3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long)**Normal activity in **gluteus medius (r/o plexopathy)** and **lumbar paraspinals (r/o radiculopathy)** absent or delayed **H-reflex**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657983880693\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] portion of the sciatic nerve is more vulnerable to injury",\n                answer: "**peroneal (fibular)** portion of the sciatic nerve is more vulnerable to injury",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1657984061306\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Tibial nerve course descends along the popliteal fossa to the distal border of the [...] muscle, superficial to it proximally, it is positioned [...] to the popliteal vessels, before crossing to the opposite side passes anterior to the [...] deep to the [...] muscle, to enter the leg in the distal one-third of the leg it is covered only by skin and fascia, sometimes overlapped by the [...]It reaches the [...], ending under the [...]where it divides into medial and lateral [...] nerves",\n                answer: "Tibial nerve course descends along the popliteal fossa to the distal border of the **popliteus** muscle, superficial to it proximally, it is positioned **lateral::side** to the popliteal vessels, before crossing to the opposite side passes anterior to the **aponeurotic arch::landmark** deep to the **soleus** muscle, to enter the leg in the distal one-third of the leg it is covered only by skin and fascia, sometimes overlapped by the **flexor hallucis longus**It reaches the **medial malleolus::bony structure**, ending under the **flexor retinaculum**where it divides into medial and lateral **plantar** nerves",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658084858130\n            },\n            {\n                question: "sural nerve, course [...] is joined by the [...], a branch of the [...] nerve descends along the calf and [...] border of the [...] to the region between the [...] and the [...].",\n                answer: "sural nerve, course **medial sural** is joined by the **sural communicating**, a branch of the **common peroneal** nerve descends along the calf and **lateral::side** border of the **Achilles tendon::anatomical landmark** to the region between the **lateral malleolus** and the **calcaneus**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658085115905\n            },\n            {\n                question: "sural nerve cutaneous It supplies the [...] and [...] skin of the distal [...] of the leg, the skin overlying the [...] [...], and the [...] aspect of the [...] and [...] the [...] branch supplies the skin of the [...]",\n                answer: "sural nerve cutaneous It supplies the **posterior** and **lateral** skin of the distal **third** of the leg, the skin overlying the **lateral** **malleolus**, and the **lateral** aspect of the **foot** and **little toe** the **medial calcaneal** branch supplies the skin of the **medial heel**",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658085647281\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Tibial N. innervatesSuperficial/proximal[...][...][...][...]Deep/distal[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Tibial N. innervatesSuperficial/proximal**Popliteus****Plantaris****Gastrocnemius****Soleus**Deep/distal**Tibialis posterior (TP)****Flexor digitorum longus (FDL)****Flexor hallucis longus (FHL)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658086162737\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel)Medial plantar nerve[...][...][...][...]Sensory branchLateral plantar nerve[...][...][...][...][...][...]Sensory branchesCalcaneal nerveSensory branch",\n                answer: "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel)Medial plantar nerve**Abductor hallucis****Flexor hallucis brevis****Flexor digitorum brevis****1st Lumbrical**Sensory branchLateral plantar nerve**Lumbricals****Interossei****Quadratus plantae****Abductor digiti minimi****Flexor digiti minimi****Adductor hallucis**Sensory branchesCalcaneal nerveSensory branch",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658086625234\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: tibial n. injured by compression under the flexor retinaculum in the medial ankle",\n                answer: "**tarsal tunnel sndrome**: tibial n. injured by compression under the flexor retinaculum in the medial ankle",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658086773238\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Tarsal tunnel syndromeClinical presentationInvolves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to [...]pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial [...] area and entire [...]It is reproduced by [...]positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited",\n                answer: "Tarsal tunnel syndromeClinical presentationInvolves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to **intrinsic foot weakness**pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial **Perimalleolar** area and entire **sole**It is reproduced by **ankle inversion**positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658087179287\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]. Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...]EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",\n                answer: "Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal **medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same**. Normal **calcaneal nerve**CMAP: Abnormal **medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same**EMGAbnormal activity in **all tibial n. foot muscles (entire sole of foot)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658087691769\n            },\n            {\n                question: "contents of the Tarsal tunnel[...][...] [...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "contents of the Tarsal tunnel**Tibialis Posterior****flexor Digitorum longus** **Post. Tib A.****Post. Tib V.****Tibial N.****Flexor Hallucis longus**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658087942869\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Common peroneal n. course curves laterally around the [...] of the [...], passing through a [...] opening in the [...] muscle. deep peroneal n. passes in between the [...] m. and [...] m.at the ankle, divides into the [...] branch to supply the extensor digitorum brevis and the [...] branch to the 1st interspace superficial peroneal n. runs between the [...] and [...] musclesand emerges at lower [...] of the leg, where it divides into lateral and medial terminal which are sensory",\n                answer: "Common peroneal n. course curves laterally around the **neck** of the **fibula**, passing through a **fibro-osseous** opening in the **peroneus longus** muscle. deep peroneal n. passes in between the **extensor digitorum longus** m. and **tibialis anterior** m.at the ankle, divides into the **lateral terminal** branch to supply the extensor digitorum brevis and the **medial terminal** branch to the 1st interspace superficial peroneal n. runs between the **peroneus longus** and **extensor digitorum longus** musclesand emerges at lower **1/3** of the leg, where it divides into lateral and medial terminal which are sensory",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658698599790\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Common peroneal cutaneous It gives off 2 cutaneous branches, the [...] nerve aka [...] this supplies the skin of the [...] aspects of the legthe [...] nerve descends medially to join the [...] to become the sural nervebranches in the fossa also supply the [...]",\n                answer: "Common peroneal cutaneous It gives off 2 cutaneous branches, the **lateral sural** nerve aka **lateral cutaneous nerve of the calf** this supplies the skin of the **anterior, lateral** aspects of the legthe **sural communicating** nerve descends medially to join the **medial sural** to become the sural nervebranches in the fossa also supply the **knee joint**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658699763997\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Superficial Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates: (2 motor 2 sensory)[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Superficial Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates: (2 motor 2 sensory)**Peroneus longus****Peroneus brevis****Medial cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum)****Lateral cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658700232615\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates:Leg[...][...][...]Foot[...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates:Leg**Tibialis Anterior****Extensor Digitorum Longus****Extensor Hallucis Longus**Foot**Peroneus tertius****Extensor Digitorum Brevis****First dorsal interossei****Dorsal digital cutaneous n. (1st Web-space)::sensory**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658700541562\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Peroneal nerve injury Etiology[...][...][...][...][...]common[...] [...]",\n                answer: "Peroneal nerve injury Etiology**prolonged leg crossing****rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)****positioning during surgery****cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)****prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)**common**metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)** **trauma (to the knee or fibula)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658701328163\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Comm. Peroneal n. injury Clinical presentation There is weakness of [...] and [...] as well a commonly weakness of [...] Loss of sensation or numbness commonly occurs over the [...] and [...][...] may be noted at the fibular head",\n                answer: "Comm. Peroneal n. injury Clinical presentation There is weakness of **foot dorsiflexion** and **extension of the toes** as well a commonly weakness of **foot eversion** Loss of sensation or numbness commonly occurs over the **antero-lateral leg** and **entire dorsum of foot****Tinel’s sign** may be noted at the fibular head",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658701692372\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Weakness of only the ankle dorsiflexors and [...] helps to clinically differentiate a [...] nerve injury from a/an: [...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Weakness of only the ankle dorsiflexors and **ankle evertors** helps to clinically differentiate a **common peroneal (fibular)** nerve injury from a/an: **L5 radiculopathy****Lumbar Plexopathy****Sciatic Neuropathy**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658702063609\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP Abnormal [...] Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...] Normal at [...] EMGAbnormal activity muscles innervated by the [...]ex. [...]ex. [...] Normal activity in [...]as well as [...]+ add on [...](not glut med, or paraspinals)",\n                answer: "Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP Abnormal **superficial peroneal (fibular)** Normal **Sural nerve**CMAP: Abnormal **above fibular head::conduction block** Normal at **ankle and below fibular head::conduction block** EMGAbnormal activity muscles innervated by the ** both superficial and deep peroneal nerves::2**ex. **Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis longus**ex. **Peroneus longus/brevis** Normal activity in **biceps femoris-short (sciatic nerve, peroneal (fibular) division \"proximal extent\")::r/o**as well as **Gastroc (S1, S2) [r/o sciatic involvement]::r/o**+ add on **Tibialis posterior (L5, S1) [r/o L5 radic]::r/o**(not glut med, or paraspinals)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658703565315\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Common peroneal nerve NCSthe [...] can be used if the EDB is atrophied",\n                answer: "Common peroneal nerve NCSthe **TA** can be used if the EDB is atrophied",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658703663248\n            },\n            {\n                question: "If... EMG is abnormal in the common peroneal nerve m's [ie. Tib. Ant. & Peroneus Longus] then... you must study the [...] to [...] of the lesion",\n                answer: "If... EMG is abnormal in the common peroneal nerve m's [ie. Tib. Ant. & Peroneus Longus] then... you must study the **biceps femoris (short head)** to **define proximal extent** of the lesion",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658704389962\n            },\n            {\n                question: "DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYAKA [...] refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the [...] of the ankle",\n                answer: "DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYAKA **anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome** refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the **inferior extensor retinaculum** of the ankle",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658704898777\n            },\n            {\n                question: "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentationmay have weakness, and atrophy of the [...] numbness and paresthesias in the [...] Pain may be located over the [...] that is relieved with [...]",\n                answer: "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentationmay have weakness, and atrophy of the **EDB** numbness and paresthesias in the **1st / 2nd web space** Pain may be located over the **dorsum of the foot** that is relieved with **motion**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658705111733\n            },\n            {\n                question: "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...] (Conduction Block)EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",\n                answer: "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal **deep peroneal (fibular) (Abnormal findings to the first web space [Never seen this done])**Normal **superficial peroneal**CMAP: Abnormal **common peroneal (fibular) Motor ALL sites (Ankle & a/b fib)** (Conduction Block)EMGAbnormal activity in **deep peroneal (fibular) innervated muscles below the ankle (ie EDB)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658705500859\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYClinical presentation:c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in [...] and [...] except for the [...] [...] weakness can also be noted",\n                answer: "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYClinical presentation:c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in **distal anterolateral calf** and **dorsal foot** except for the **1st webspace** **Foot eversion** weakness can also be noted",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658706239543\n            },\n            {\n                question: "superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findingsNCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]Normal [...]CMAP: Normal [...][...]EMGAbnormal activity in [...]normal findings in [...]",\n                answer: "superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findingsNCSSNAP: Abnormal **superficial peroneal (fibular) sensory**Normal **sural sensory**CMAP: Normal **common peroneal Motor (from deep fib)****Tibial Motor (Superficial peroneal motor, not available)**EMGAbnormal activity in **peroneus longus and/or peroneus brevis**normal findings in **deep peroneal (fibular) nerve innervated muscles ie Tib. Ant.**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1658706482385\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] nerve: anomalous branch from the [...] nerve that travels [...] to the [...] to innervate some or all of the [...]",\n                answer: "**accessory peroneal (fibular)** nerve: anomalous branch from the **superficial peroneal (fibular)** nerve that travels **posterior** to the **lateral malleolus** to innervate some or all of the **extensor digitorum brevis (EDB)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660572795623\n            },\n            {\n                question: "accessory deep peroneal nerve can be recognized by a CMAP that is [...] with stimulation of the peroneal nerve at [...] site than at the [...] site",\n                answer: "accessory deep peroneal nerve can be recognized by a CMAP that is **larger** with stimulation of the peroneal nerve at **b/a knee** site than at the **ankle** site",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660573274951\n            },\n            {\n                question: "accessory peroneal (fibular) n.can be confirmed by [...]",\n                answer: "accessory peroneal (fibular) n.can be confirmed by **stimulating posterior to the lateral malleolus**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660573374270\n            },\n            {\n                question: "in a patient with a dominant accessory deep peroneal nerve and common peroneal neuropathy at the fibular head due to conduction block, stimulation of the peroneal n. at the [...] and [...] site may fail to elicit a CMAPwhereas...stimulation of the peroneal n. at the [...] may elicit the only recordable motor response",\n                answer: "in a patient with a dominant accessory deep peroneal nerve and common peroneal neuropathy at the fibular head due to conduction block, stimulation of the peroneal n. at the **ankle** and **above the knee** site may fail to elicit a CMAPwhereas...stimulation of the peroneal n. at the **below the knee** may elicit the only recordable motor response",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660573872784\n            },\n            {\n                question: "accessory peroneal n.with this anomalous innervation... the EDB can be spared with a [...] nerve injury",\n                answer: "accessory peroneal n.with this anomalous innervation... the EDB can be spared with a **deep peroneal (aka anterior tarsal tunnel)** nerve injury",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660574107712\n            },\n            {\n                question: "sural n. fibers originate from branches of the [...] and [...] nerves",\n                answer: "sural n. fibers originate from branches of the **tibial** and **common peroneal (fibular)** nerves",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660574613729\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology:[...][...]trauma (e.g., laceration)",\n                answer: "SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology:**compression from tight socks****Baker’s/ganglion cyst**trauma (e.g., laceration)",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660574731223\n            },\n            {\n                question: "sural neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...]EMG[...]",\n                answer: "sural neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal sural sensory**CMAP: **not applicable**EMG**Not applicable**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660574868491\n            },\n            {\n                question: "superior gluteal n. course leaves the pelvis via the [...] [...] the piriformis muscle and divides into superior and inferior branchesinferior branch supplies [...]superior branch supplies the [...]",\n                answer: "superior gluteal n. course leaves the pelvis via the **greater sciatic foramen** **above** the piriformis muscle and divides into superior and inferior branchesinferior branch supplies **glute med, min, and TFL**superior branch supplies the **gluteus medius only**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660584865380\n            },\n            {\n                question: "gluteal n. injury etiology [...][...][...]not hip dislocation / pelvic fracture",\n                answer: "gluteal n. injury etiology **hip joint replacement****improper IM injection****pelvic masses**not hip dislocation / pelvic fracture",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660585022915\n            },\n            {\n                question: "gluteal n. injury clinical pressuperior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [...] and [...]. [...] will be seeninferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [...].",\n                answer: "gluteal n. injury clinical pressuperior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of **hip abduction** and **internal/external rotation**. **Trendelenburg gait::phys-ex** will be seeninferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of **hip extension**.",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660585180134\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator n. course descends within the substance of the [...], emerging from its medial border at the pelvic brimdescends along the ala of the sacrum to reach the lateral pelvic wall on the [...] musclesweeps forward within the pelvis to reach and pass through the [...] to enter the thigh then it divides into anterior and posterior branches",\n                answer: "Obturator n. course descends within the substance of the **psoas major**, emerging from its medial border at the pelvic brimdescends along the ala of the sacrum to reach the lateral pelvic wall on the **obturator internus** musclesweeps forward within the pelvis to reach and pass through the **obturator foramen** to enter the thigh then it divides into anterior and posterior branches",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660586818671\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator Nerve Innervates...anterior branch[...][...][...][...]posterior branch [...][...]Sensory Branch[...] [...]",\n                answer: "Obturator Nerve Innervates...anterior branch**adductor longus****adductor brevis****gracilis****pectineus***posterior branch **obturator externus****adductor magnus^**Sensory Branch**articular knee joint** **medial aspect of the thigh**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660587113470\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator neuropathy, Etiology:[...][...][...]tumorgravid uterusgi surgery/positioning",\n                answer: "Obturator neuropathy, Etiology:**retroperitonneal hematoma****pelvic fracture****obturator hernia**tumorgravid uterusgi surgery/positioning",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660587473171\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator neuropathy, Clinical presentation:altered sensation in the [...] region (common)including pain, numbness, and/or paresthesiasweakness with hip [...] and [...]",\n                answer: "Obturator neuropathy, Clinical presentation:altered sensation in the **inguinal/medial thigh** region (common)including pain, numbness, and/or paresthesiasweakness with hip **ADduction** and **internal rotation**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660587596274\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator n. injury During ambulation, they present with a [...] and [...] gait",\n                answer: "Obturator n. injury During ambulation, they present with a **wide-based** and **circumducting** gait",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660587685186\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Obturator neuroptathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...]EMGAbnormal activity: [...]",\n                answer: "Obturator neuroptathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **None available**CMAP: **None available**EMGAbnormal activity: **in the obturator n. innervated m's (eg. adductor’s & gracillus)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660587841056\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Peripheral Neuropathies categorized based on distribution effected they can be described as [...] or [...]",\n                answer: "Peripheral Neuropathies categorized based on distribution effected they can be described as **diffuse** or **multifocal**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660870959722\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Inherited Peripheral Neuropathiestypically categorized as:[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Inherited Peripheral Neuropathiestypically categorized as:**Hereditary motor and sensory neuropathies (HMSN)****Hereditary sensory and autonomic neuropathies (HSAN)****Hereditary motor neuropathies (HMN)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660871625182\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] aka [...] disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the [...] gene, located within the chromosome [...]",\n                answer: "**HMSN** aka **Charcot–Marie–Tooth** disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the **PMP-22** gene, located within the chromosome **17p11. 2**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660871742456\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Acquired Neuropathiesmost commonly related to:[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Acquired Neuropathiesmost commonly related to:**Diabetes mellitus (most common)****Acute inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculopathy (AIDP)****Medications**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660871898661\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Acquired Peripheral Neuropathies[...] can manifest as a polyradiculopathy",\n                answer: "Acquired Peripheral Neuropathies**Demyelinating inflammatory neuropathies** can manifest as a polyradiculopathy",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660872097300\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Clinical Presentation of Peripheral Polyneruopathies A classic triad has been described presenting in the lower limbs > upper limbs:[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Clinical Presentation of Peripheral Polyneruopathies A classic triad has been described presenting in the lower limbs > upper limbs:**Sensory changes in a stocking/glove distribution****Distal weakness****Diminished/absent Reflexes**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660872292169\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Clinical Presentation of Poly Neuropathies acquired polyneuropathies:[...][...]inherited polyneuropathies:[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Clinical Presentation of Poly Neuropathies acquired polyneuropathies:**Burning / Pain::sx****Paresthesias::sx**inherited polyneuropathies:**Sensory loss::phys-ex/sx****Ataxia::phys-ex****muscle cramping::sx**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660872414800\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG/NCSdiagnostic criteria for peripheral neuropathy consists of evaluating at least [...]",\n                answer: "EMG/NCSdiagnostic criteria for peripheral neuropathy consists of evaluating at least **three limbs**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660872621828\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Peripheral NeuropathyEDX abnormalities can include:Prolonged latencies (o/l)Increased conduction velocities (CV)Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv)Decreased [...] (“missing” waveforms on [...] stimulations)Increased [...] (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on [...] stimulation \"duration\")",\n                answer: "Peripheral NeuropathyEDX abnormalities can include:Prolonged latencies (o/l)Increased conduction velocities (CV)Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv)Decreased **persistence** (“missing” waveforms on **repetitive::same** stimulations)Increased **chronodispersion** (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on **repetitive::same** stimulation \"duration\")",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660872880976\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Ddx Foot Drop[...][...][...][...][...]",\n                answer: "Ddx Foot Drop**Central: Tumor, cerebrovascular accident (CVA), arteriovenous malformation (AVM), spinal cord injury (SCI)****Radiculopathy: L4–L5::2****Plexopathy****Mononeuropathy: peroneal (fibular) portion of the sciatic nerve, common peroneal (fibular), deep peroneal (fibular)::3****Diffuse polyneuropathy: Diabetes**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660873371807\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth diseasethe PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with [...]. which presents with [...] and [...] episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",\n                answer: "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth diseasethe PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with **liability to pressure palsy (HNPP)**. which presents with **recurrent** and **short-term** episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1660873646296\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NCS in peripheral neruopathyConduction Block is more likely to be seen in [...] polyneuropathies",\n                answer: "NCS in peripheral neruopathyConduction Block is more likely to be seen in **acquired::inherited/acquired** polyneuropathies",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1661097058583\n            },\n            {\n                question: "peripheral neuropathies classicaly present with stocking-glove patternThough less common, [...] may demonstrate abnormalities first",\n                answer: "peripheral neuropathies classicaly present with stocking-glove patternThough less common, **the upper limbs** may demonstrate abnormalities first",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1661097187573\n            },\n            {\n                question: "ABductor HallucisInnervation is via the...[...] nerve[...] roots",\n                answer: "ABductor HallucisInnervation is via the...**medial plantar (tibial n, tibial division of the sciatic n, sacral plexus)** nerve**S1, S2** roots",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1662309330327\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Extensor Digitorum Brevis Innervation is via the... [...] nerve[...] roots",\n                answer: "Extensor Digitorum Brevis Innervation is via the... **deep peroneal** nerve**L5, S1** roots",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1662309866736\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] needle electrode",\n                answer: "**Single-fiber** needle electrode",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1673315693225\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG Special StudiesSmall nerve fiber abnormalities and associated [...] dysfunctionmay not be seen with conventional NCS and can require additional tests",\n                answer: "EMG Special StudiesSmall nerve fiber abnormalities and associated **autonomic** dysfunctionmay not be seen with conventional NCS and can require additional tests",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698072349804\n            },\n            {\n                question: "EMG Special StudiesFurthermore, small fiber neuropathies manifest as [...] in the extremities with abnormal pinprick sensation but demonstrate [...] standard NCS",\n                answer: "EMG Special StudiesFurthermore, small fiber neuropathies manifest as **burning pain::sx** in the extremities with abnormal pinprick sensation but demonstrate **normal** standard NCS",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698072428074\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories)[...][...] [...] [...] [...]",\n                answer: "**Axonal** Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories)**HMSN-II::inherited disorder****Heavy metals: Lead, Gold, Mercury** **Cancer drugs: Vincristine, Cis-platinum** **Metabolic derangements: alcohol, B12 deficiency, folate deficiency** **Auto-immune: paraneoplastic syndrome, Sjogren's, Crohn's, Sarcoidosis**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698073028485\n            },\n            {\n                question: "HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: AbnormalCMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by [...]%No [...]No [...]No [...] EMG[...]",\n                answer: "HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: AbnormalCMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by **70**%No **temporal dispersion**No **conduction block**No **focal slowing (diffuse slowing** EMG**Normal**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698073351226\n            },\n            {\n                question: "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsNCSSNAP: [...]CMAP:[...] CV / o/p latecny[...]: amplitudeNCS CMAP will be positive for [...][...][...] [...]: [...] EMG [...]",\n                answer: "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsNCSSNAP: **Abnormal**CMAP:**Abnormal** CV / o/p latecny**normal (unless poor prognosis)**: amplitudeNCS CMAP will be positive for **temporal dispersion****conduction block****focal slowing** **F-wave**: **Abnormal—first EDX sign** EMG **typically Normal (unless axonal variant)**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698073731663\n            },\n            {\n                question: "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsPoorer prognosis if:CMAP: Amplitude <[...]% of normal NCV <[...]% of normal[...]EMG: [...]",\n                answer: "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsPoorer prognosis if:CMAP: Amplitude <**20**% of normal NCV <**40**% of normal**F-wave: Absent**EMG: **Abnormal activity (axonal involvement)**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698073824473\n            },\n            {\n                question: "HIV-Related Neuropathies[...]: most common type of neuropathyprimarily affects [...] and [...] fibersparesthesias begin in the [...] followed by the [...]",\n                answer: "HIV-Related Neuropathies**Distal Symmetric Poly-neuropathy**: most common type of neuropathyprimarily affects **sensory** and **autonomic** fibersparesthesias begin in the **toes** followed by the **fingers**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698074457938\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low [...] causes the amplitude of the [...] to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber APThis occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content",\n                answer: "NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low **safety factor** causes the amplitude of the **endplate potentials** to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber APThis occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698586431927\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Myasthenia gravis (MG): disorder resulting in a decreased quantal response due to an autoimmune response against postsynaptic ACh receptorsleads to [...] [...] amplitudes, and [...] frequency (quantal content is normal)",\n                answer: "Myasthenia gravis (MG): disorder resulting in a decreased quantal response due to an autoimmune response against postsynaptic ACh receptorsleads to **reduced** **miniature endplate potential (MEPP)** amplitudes, and **normal** frequency (quantal content is normal)",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698586614202\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS, myasthenic syndrome): disorder resulting in decreased quantal content leaving the presynaptic cleft, resulting in [...] MEPP amplitudes with [...] frequency (quantal response is normal)",\n                answer: "Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS, myasthenic syndrome): disorder resulting in decreased quantal content leaving the presynaptic cleft, resulting in **normal** MEPP amplitudes with **decreased** frequency (quantal response is normal)",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698586679571\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MG pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response in which polyclonal antibodies are directed against the Muscle Specific Tyrosine Kinase (MuSK) of the [...]",\n                answer: "MG pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response in which polyclonal antibodies are directed against the Muscle Specific Tyrosine Kinase (MuSK) of the **postsynaptic membrane**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698587203068\n            },\n            {\n                question: "LEMS pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response against the voltage gated [...] channels on the [...] membrane",\n                answer: "LEMS pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response against the voltage gated **P/Q Ca2+** channels on the **presynaptic** membrane",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698587321136\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In MG MSR are [...]In LEMS MSR are [...]",\n                answer: "In MG MSR are **normal**In LEMS MSR are **abnormal**",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698613895401\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Myesthenia Gravis DxLabs[...][...]",\n                answer: "Myesthenia Gravis DxLabs**Anti-Ach receptor antibodies****Anti-MuSK antibodies**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698613966047\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Lambert Eaton DxLabsAntibodies against [...]",\n                answer: "Lambert Eaton DxLabsAntibodies against **voltage-gated Ca+ channels**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698613999568\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ disorders muscle biopsy MG[...] of the postjunctional membrane with loss of junctional folds and receptorsLEMS[...] of neuromuscular junction with decreased active zones",\n                answer: "NMJ disorders muscle biopsy MG**Simplification** of the postjunctional membrane with loss of junctional folds and receptorsLEMS**Overdevelopment** of neuromuscular junction with decreased active zones",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614182352\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Evaluation of NMJ d/o involves typical NCS with EMG, as well as the addition of [...] and [...]",\n                answer: "Evaluation of NMJ d/o involves typical NCS with EMG, as well as the addition of **repetitive nerve stimulations (RNSs)** and **single-fiber EMG (SFEMG)**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614339816\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS:SNAP: [...]^CMAP: [...]& o/p latency and conduction velocity [...]* amplitude except in [...]",\n                answer: "NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS:SNAP: **normal**^CMAP: **normal**& o/p latency and conduction velocity **variable (MG: normal)*** amplitude except in **LEMS**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614538656\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ d/o EdxIf low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a [...] [...], followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >[...]% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",\n                answer: "NMJ d/o EdxIf low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a **10 second::time** **maximum voluntary contraction**, followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >**100**% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614653830\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ d/o EdxCMAP amplitude will show >[...]% [...] on low rate rep. stim",\n                answer: "NMJ d/o EdxCMAP amplitude will show >**10**% **decrement** on low rate rep. stim",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614743939\n            },\n            {\n                question: "NMJ disorder Edx findingsEMG: Can be normal or abnormalIn severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen[...], [...] MUAPs with [...] recruitment are associated with [...]MUAPs become [...]",\n                answer: "NMJ disorder Edx findingsEMG: Can be normal or abnormalIn severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen**Short-duration**, **low-amplitude** MUAPs with **early** recruitment are associated with **blocking::SFEMG parameter**MUAPs become **unstable**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698614911244\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Myesthenia Gravis Treatment [...][...]CorticosteroidsImmunosuppressive agentsPlasmapheresisIV Immunoglobulin",\n                answer: "Myesthenia Gravis Treatment **Thymectomy****Anticholinesterase drugs: Pyridostigmine**CorticosteroidsImmunosuppressive agentsPlasmapheresisIV Immunoglobulin",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698615055320\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Lambert Eaton SnydrometreatmentTreat [...][...][...]: Increases ACh quanta3,4-diaminopyridine",\n                answer: "Lambert Eaton SnydrometreatmentTreat **malignancy****Immunosuppressives: Corticosteroids, steroid-sparing agents, PLEX, IVIG::category****Guanidine**: Increases ACh quanta3,4-diaminopyridine",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698615157413\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Botulismtreatment [...] in first [...] hoursSupportive with intubation for respiratory failureRecovery occurs from collateral sprouting",\n                answer: "Botulismtreatment **trivalent ABE antitoxin** in first **24** hoursSupportive with intubation for respiratory failureRecovery occurs from collateral sprouting",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1698615238655\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to [...]",\n                answer: "**Arthrogryposis**: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to **intrauterine hypomobility**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705599486655\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Myopathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: [...]^^CMAP: [...] amplitude**[...] latencies and conduction velocities&&EMGClassic findings: are [...], [...], [...] MUAP's with [...] recruitment Resting activity: [...], [...], [...]",\n                answer: "Myopathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: **Normal**^^CMAP: **typically normal, (Decreased in significant atrophy/preferential distal m.'s)** amplitude****Normal** latencies and conduction velocities&&EMGClassic findings: are **low amplitude**, **short duration**, **polyphasic** MUAP's with **early** recruitment Resting activity: **fibs/sharps**, **myotonic discharges**, **CRD's (depends on the type of disorder)**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705599990528\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Quantitative EMGprovides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform [...], which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing [...]. The mean [...] is calculated using [...] MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line.",\n                answer: "Quantitative EMGprovides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform **duration::same**, which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing **myopathies**. The mean **duration::same** is calculated using **20::#** MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line.",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705600055647\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationshort-duration, small amplitudepossible causedue to [...]",\n                answer: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationshort-duration, small amplitudepossible causedue to **loss of muscle fibers**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705600246289\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationlong-duration, large amplitudepossible causethese polyphasic potentials are due to [...]",\n                answer: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationlong-duration, large amplitudepossible causethese polyphasic potentials are due to **collateral sprouting**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705600318139\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentation[...]possible causevariable amplitude potentials are due to [...] of [...], formed at the beginning of [...]",\n                answer: "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentation**Unstable**possible causevariable amplitude potentials are due to **blocking** of **immature NMJs**, formed at the beginning of **collateral sprouting**",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705600493013\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MyopathiesRepetitive Nerve StimulationA normal or a decremental response can occurThis is due to the [...] found in regenerating immature NMJs that form during recovery or reinnervation",\n                answer: "MyopathiesRepetitive Nerve StimulationA normal or a decremental response can occurThis is due to the **reduced safety factor** found in regenerating immature NMJs that form during recovery or reinnervation",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705601463152\n            },\n            {\n                question: "MyopathiesSingle-Fiber EMG (may demonstrate):[...][...][...]",\n                answer: "MyopathiesSingle-Fiber EMG (may demonstrate):**increased jitter****increased fiber density (FD)****increased blocking**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705601700676\n            },\n            {\n                question: "TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY[...] [...]Fiber type disproportion",\n                answer: "TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY**Myotonic Dystrophy** **Nemaline rod myopathy**Fiber type disproportion",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705601821176\n            },\n            {\n                question: "TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY[...][...]Deconditioning",\n                answer: "TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY**Steroid myopathy****Myasthenia gravis**Deconditioning",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705601871067\n            },\n            {\n                question: "FSH, facioscapulohumeralinheritance: [...]",\n                answer: "FSH, facioscapulohumeralinheritance: **autosomal dominant**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705602018547\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Central Core disease is associated with [...]",\n                answer: "Central Core disease is associated with **malignant hyperthermia**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705602109923\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Inclusion Body Myositisetiology: unkownpresentation: [...], painless weakness in proximal and distal muscles onset: affects [...]Edx findings: unique to myopathy [...]treatment: no treatment",\n                answer: "Inclusion Body Myositisetiology: unkownpresentation: **assymetric**, painless weakness in proximal and distal muscles onset: affects **adults age 45-55 (peaks at 70)::epidimiology**Edx findings: unique to myopathy **abnormal NCS (assoc w/ polyneuropathy)**treatment: no treatment",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705602339071\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SMA, spinal muscle atrophyportion of motor neuron affected[...]",\n                answer: "SMA, spinal muscle atrophyportion of motor neuron affected**lower motor neuron**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705603400131\n            },\n            {\n                question: "motor neuron disease [...][...]portion of motor neuron affectedupper motor neuron",\n                answer: "motor neuron disease **PLS, primary lateral sclerosis****Hereditary spastic paraplegia**portion of motor neuron affectedupper motor neuron",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705603481394\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor Neuron DiseaseIt is important to rule out treatable neuropathies that mimic motor neuron disease (MND). An example of this is [...], which includes conduction block and temporal dispersion, not seen in MND.",\n                answer: "Motor Neuron DiseaseIt is important to rule out treatable neuropathies that mimic motor neuron disease (MND). An example of this is **multifocal motor neuropathy**, which includes conduction block and temporal dispersion, not seen in MND.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705603542062\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsNCSSNAP: [...]** CMAP:[...]: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies^^ [...]: amplitude&&F-wave: [...], [...] with [...]",\n                answer: "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsNCSSNAP: **normal**** CMAP:**typicaly normal**: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies^^ **reduced**: amplitude&&F-wave: **Abnormal latency**, **persistence** with **chronodispersion**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705603808912\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsEMGStudy at least [...] limbsClassic Needle Finding: [...] and [...]must be found in [...] of [...] body segmentsAt least [...] muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",\n                answer: "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsEMGStudy at least **3** limbsClassic Needle Finding: **Active denervation with reinnervation::in general** and **fasciculations::MUAP morphology**must be found in **3** of **4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)** body segmentsAt least **2** muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604036733\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:degradation of neural tissue due to multiple medical complications causing a primarily axonal as well as demyelinating motor and sensory peripheral polyneuropathy",\n                answer: "**critical illness polyneuropathy (CIP)**:degradation of neural tissue due to multiple medical complications causing a primarily axonal as well as demyelinating motor and sensory peripheral polyneuropathy",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604444081\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:an acute, generally inflammatory myopathy due to multiple medical complications causing muscle membrane instability and muscle cell breakdown",\n                answer: "**critical illness myopathy (CIM)**:an acute, generally inflammatory myopathy due to multiple medical complications causing muscle membrane instability and muscle cell breakdown",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604514949\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CNS disorders Edx FindingsIn CNS disorders, sensory and motor NCSs are normal.On needle EMG, there is no denervation or reinnervation on the weak limb(s); it reveals normal spontaneous activity and normal MUAP morphology. On voluntary contraction, recruitment is [...]",\n                answer: "CNS disorders Edx FindingsIn CNS disorders, sensory and motor NCSs are normal.On needle EMG, there is no denervation or reinnervation on the weak limb(s); it reveals normal spontaneous activity and normal MUAP morphology. On voluntary contraction, recruitment is **normal**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604754425\n            },\n            {\n                question: "SCI edx findings will EMG be abdnormal: [...]",\n                answer: "SCI edx findings will EMG be abdnormal: **yes (at the level of the lesion)**",\n                category: "Study Notes",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604833796\n            },\n            {\n                question: "paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS)related cancerssmall cell lung cancer [...][...]",\n                answer: "paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS)related cancerssmall cell lung cancer **lymphoma****myeloma**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705604994520\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Paraneoplastic Syndrome can affect the CNS e.g.[...] and paraneoplastic [...]",\n                answer: "Paraneoplastic Syndrome can affect the CNS e.g.**limbic encephalitis (hippocampus and amygdala)** and paraneoplastic **cerebellar degeneration**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705605192334\n            },\n            {\n                question: "In ALS [...], [...], and [...] are spared",\n                answer: "In ALS **bowel**, **bladder**, and **sensation** are spared",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705605280038\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Repetitive nerve stimulation:These are studies in which a [...] [...] stimulation of a motor nerve is performed.A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic [...].",\n                answer: "Repetitive nerve stimulation:These are studies in which a **repeated** **supramaximal** stimulation of a motor nerve is performed.A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic **amplitude changes**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705605630890\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation (RNS) SETUP[...] the electrode[...] the limbStimulate at a supramaximal levelOptimize limb temperature (approximately [...])Minimize [...]Stop [...]Muscles should be evaluated in a [...] progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated)",\n                answer: "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation (RNS) SETUP**Immobilize** the electrode**Immobilize** the limbStimulate at a supramaximal levelOptimize limb temperature (approximately **30°C**)Minimize **electrode gel**Stop **anticholinesterase inhibitors**Muscles should be evaluated in a **distal to proximal** progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705605825351\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ABNORMALITYA >[...]% decrease in amplitude from the [...] to [...] waveform is significant for pathology",\n                answer: "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ABNORMALITYA >**10**% decrease in amplitude from the **1st** to **5th** waveform is significant for pathology",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705605875689\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [...] to [...] HzEach stimulus causes the [...] amplitude to drop. If the [...] is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the [...] amplitude",\n                answer: "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of **2** to **3** HzEach stimulus causes the **EPP** amplitude to drop. If the **safety factor** is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the **MUAP** amplitude",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606092506\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >[...]% amplitude reduction between the [...] and [...] waveformsAn increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of [...]A typical [...] decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",\n                answer: "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >**10**% amplitude reduction between the **1st** and **4th** waveformsAn increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of **secondary ACh stores**A typical **U-shaped** decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606211188\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second [...] or [...] stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",\n                answer: "**Postactivation Facilitation (PAF)**:After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second **isometric contraction** or **tetany-producing** stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606483378\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a [...] performed every [...] for [...] after an initial 30-60-second isometric contractionThis test should be used if a [...] is not seen with the initial [...], but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",\n                answer: "**Postactivation Exhaustion (PAE)**:This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a **LRRS::same** performed every **minute** for **5 minutes** after an initial 30-60-second isometric contractionThis test should be used if a **decrement** is not seen with the initial **LRRS::same**, but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606612331\n            },\n            {\n                question: "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [...] to [...] Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists [...] and repairs the waveformstypically performed if a patient is unable to perform a [...] [...]",\n                answer: "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of **10** to **50** Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists **ACh release** and repairs the waveformstypically performed if a patient is unable to perform a **30- to 60-second::time** ** maximal isometric contraction**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606836309\n            },\n            {\n                question: "High-Rate Repetitive StimulationNMJ disease and Amplitude Changes[...] = 200%–300% increment[...] = Decrement demonstrated and partially repaired",\n                answer: "High-Rate Repetitive StimulationNMJ disease and Amplitude Changes**LEMS** = 200%–300% increment**MG** = Decrement demonstrated and partially repaired",\n                category: "Nerve Conduction",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705606938148\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Pseudofacilitation a normal reaction and demonstrates a progressive increase in [...] with HRRS or voluntary muscle contraction",\n                answer: "Pseudofacilitation a normal reaction and demonstrates a progressive increase in **CMAP amplitude** with HRRS or voluntary muscle contraction",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705608346612\n            },\n            {\n                question: "PseudofacilitationIt represents a decrease in [...] due to increased [...] of muscle fiber contraction",\n                answer: "PseudofacilitationIt represents a decrease in **temporal dispersion** due to increased **synchronicity** of muscle fiber contraction",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705608406408\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Single Fiber EMGThis is a study that monitors the parameters of single muscle fiber APs. It is useful if [...] is normal (and an abnormal diagnosis is still suspected)",\n                answer: "Single Fiber EMGThis is a study that monitors the parameters of single muscle fiber APs. It is useful if **repetitive stimulation** is normal (and an abnormal diagnosis is still suspected)",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705608757494\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Single Fiber EMGSFEMG is the most sensitive test for [...] but has low specificityAbnormalities can also be associated with [...], and [...]",\n                answer: "Single Fiber EMGSFEMG is the most sensitive test for **NMJ disorders** but has low specificityAbnormalities can also be associated with **motor neuron disorders**, and **peripheral neuropathies**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705608811032\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Single Fiber EMG ParamtersFiber densityrepresents the number of [...] belonging to the same [...] within the recording radius of the electrodeA FD of [...] is normal. Higher than this represents a [...] process",\n                answer: "Single Fiber EMG ParamtersFiber densityrepresents the number of **single muscle fibers** belonging to the same **motor unit** within the recording radius of the electrodeA FD of **1.5::decimal** is normal. Higher than this represents a **denervation and reinnervation** process",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705609068483\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Single Fiber EMG Paramters[...]:caused by a increased delay in the [...] [...] of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve injury results in poor activation of the immature NMJs",\n                answer: "Single Fiber EMG Paramters**Jitter**:caused by a increased delay in the **inter-potential** **discharges** of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve injury results in poor activation of the immature NMJs",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705609548120\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Single Fiber EMG parameters[...]:This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP [...]It occurs if the jitter becomes >[...] μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",\n                answer: "Single Fiber EMG parameters**Blocking**:This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP **fails to appear**It occurs if the jitter becomes >**100** μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705609677196\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: [...]: amplitude[...]: CV o/p latencyCMAP: [...]: amplitude[...]: CV o/p latencyEMG[...] seen in [...] musclesrecruitment patter: [...]",\n                answer: "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: **low/unobtainable**: amplitude**mild slowing**: CV o/p latencyCMAP: **low/unobtainable**: amplitude**mild slowing (primarily axonal)**: CV o/p latencyEMG**Fibs/sharps** seen in **distal** musclesrecruitment patter: **neuropathic (decreased with high frequency)**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705676555483\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Critical Illness Myopathy Edx Findingsin general will present exactly the same as [...]",\n                answer: "Critical Illness Myopathy Edx Findingsin general will present exactly the same as **myopathies**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705676719708\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:a means of evaluating the unmyelinated, [...] nerve fibers of the PNS",\n                answer: "**Sympathetic skin response**:a means of evaluating the unmyelinated, **sympathetic::same** nerve fibers of the PNS",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705678128655\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Sinus arrhythmia study: aka [...] study dependent on the normal [...] that occur with [...] via parasympathetic activitytest consists of measuring the [...] with an [...] machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",\n                answer: "Sinus arrhythmia study: aka **cardio-vagal innervation** study dependent on the normal **heart rate variations** that occur with **respiration** via parasympathetic activitytest consists of measuring the **R-R ratio** with an **EKG** machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705678658015\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] study:heart rate varies in response to changes in blood pressure and intrathoracic pressure via sympathetic and parasympathetic activity. Four phases are measured using a standard EMG machine. The findings measured in Phase 2 and Phase 4 are used for monitoring. Phase 2 should demonstrate a heart rate increase, while Phase 4 should demonstrate a decrease in the normal population.",\n                answer: "**Valsalva ratio** study:heart rate varies in response to changes in blood pressure and intrathoracic pressure via sympathetic and parasympathetic activity. Four phases are measured using a standard EMG machine. The findings measured in Phase 2 and Phase 4 are used for monitoring. Phase 2 should demonstrate a heart rate increase, while Phase 4 should demonstrate a decrease in the normal population.",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705678741145\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Anal sphincter activity:EMG recording of the external anal sphincter has [...] activity at rest.",\n                answer: "Anal sphincter activity:EMG recording of the external anal sphincter has **continuous** activity at rest.",\n                category: "Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705678820786\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Autonomic Nerve Studies[...]Sympathetic Skin ResponseSinus ArryhthmiaValsalva RatioAnal Sphincter Activity",\n                answer: "Autonomic Nerve Studies**Norepinephrine synthesis and release**Sympathetic Skin ResponseSinus ArryhthmiaValsalva RatioAnal Sphincter Activity",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705678973246\n            },\n            {\n                question: "AIDP clinical presentationsx's worst at [...] after onset [...] ascending paralysis[...][...] and [...] muscle may be affected [...]",\n                answer: "AIDP clinical presentationsx's worst at **4 weeks::time** after onset **symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric** ascending paralysis**absent reflexes****bulbar (bell's plasy)** and **respiratory** muscle may be affected **autonomic dysfunction**",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705684472999\n            },\n            {\n                question: "CIDP can present identical to AIDPCIDP should be considered:If the disease progresses for more than [...] or if [...]",\n                answer: "CIDP can present identical to AIDPCIDP should be considered:If the disease progresses for more than **8 weeks** or if **the patient relapses**",\n                category: "Clinical Conditions",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705685690177\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an [...] [...] disorder",\n                answer: "**Multifocal Motor Neuropathy**: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an **assymetric::symetric/assymetric** **pure motor::sensory/motor/mixed** disorder",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705687535103\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Firing Rate:This is the number of times a [...]. It is expressed in [...] and is calculated by dividing [...] by the [...]. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using [...]",\n                answer: "Firing Rate:This is the number of times a ** MUAP fires per second**. It is expressed in **Hz** and is calculated by dividing **1,000::#** by the **interspike interval (II)**. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using **msec**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705847730502\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:this is defined as the [...] of the [...] when [...]Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a [...] process",\n                answer: "**Recruitment frequency (RF)**:this is defined as the **Firing Rate** of the **1st MUAP** when **a 2nd MUAP begins to fire**Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a **neuropathic** process",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705849033291\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:This is the [...] between two discharges of the [...] when [...]. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately [...] msec",\n                answer: "**Recruitment interval (RI)**:This is the **interspike interval (in milliseconds)** between two discharges of the **(same) 1st MUAP** when **a second MUAP begins to fire**. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately **100** msec",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705849404362\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Decreased RI (Increased RF):would be consistent with a [...]",\n                answer: "Decreased RI (Increased RF):would be consistent with a **neuropathic process**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705849527474\n            },\n            {\n                question: "Increased RI (Decreased RF):is consistent with a [...]",\n                answer: "Increased RI (Decreased RF):is consistent with a **myopathic process**",\n                category: "General Knowledge",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705849585386\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...]:This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the [...] of the [...] by the [...]. The normal RR is considered <[...]",\n                answer: "**Recruitment ratio (RR)**:This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the **Firing Rate** of the **first MUAP** by the **number of different MUAPs on the screen**. The normal RR is considered <**10**",\n                category: "EMG Findings",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705849960072\n            },\n            {\n                question: "[...] PatternsThis is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs.It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during [...]. It is composed of [...] plus [...].It can be decreased in [...] and [...].",\n                answer: "**Interference** PatternsThis is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs.It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during **a maximum voluntary contraction**. It is composed of **recruitment** plus **activation**.It can be decreased in **CNS diseases** and **poor patient cooperation (pain, hysteria)**.",\n                category: "Muscle Anatomy",\n                type: "cloze_deletion",\n                id: 1705850435876\n            }\n        ];